B-B-Band Collab
Oligobeito
The Hamukitada
Chekera Babies
Shimo-Kitazawa
I'm just awful.
Oh... But you at least managed
to play it to the en—
About that, though!
Y-Yes?
I just realized, I'm supposed
to do vocals too, right?
But I can't sing while I'm focusing
all my motor control on the guitar.
I... I see...
I was thinking it might be better
for the band if I just sang...
But then I wouldn't have anything
to do during interludes,
and I'd probably start fidgeting on stage...
Oh, um... Yeah!
So...
I guess I'd better work harder!
Kit-aura!
My eyes!
N-Nothing.
Her eager self-improvement power
is too bright to look directly at!
But are you sure it's all right
for me to sing?
I know! You should sing with me!
N-N-Not happening!
B-But...
N-N-N-N-N-N-N-N-N...
I'm sorry. Is it that unpleasant a thought?
Hey, nice one.
Is that some new guitar showmanship move?
Senpai!
Do you like it?
Then I'll practice it too!
You don't need to practice that.
Ryo's here, so let's meet up at the club!
Right!
We will now begin the band meeting!
Round of applause!
Now, here's today's topic!
The question:
How can we be
more band-like?
How can we be more band-like?
It's so half-assed!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#04 Jumping Girl(s)
How can we be
more band-like?
Now that we've got a full member lineup,
I figured the first order of business
was to get us acting more band-like!
I... I see!
I know practice is crucial,
but there's gotta be more to us than that!
I think we should talk
about all kinds of stuff!
Is she trying to give Kita-san
a break from all her practice?
One tactic is to nail the
superficial stuff first!
Oh, that totally works!
Like if you start imitating a new popular
make-up technique and end up looking great!
Exactly!
It's like they're speaking
a foreign language...
And with that in mind...
I made us band merch!
That's a more superficial
starting point than I expected!
Did you just put a zip tie around your wrist?
Cute, huh? They come in all colors!
We'll sell them for 500 yen a piece.
What a ripoff!
650 if they're signed.
What a steal! I'll take one!
Won't that just be circulating
money within the band?
Anyone else with ideas
for becoming more band-like?
I can set us up an Isstagram and run it!
Great idea!
I hereby appoint you
Minister of Social Media!
And I'll post every day when the time comes!
And...
What about forming a fan club?
That's awfully hasty!
10,000 yen annual membership fee.
That's awfully expensive!
Membership perks include meet-and-greets
and a once-a-year takoyaki party with the band.
The fans bring the ingredients.
What a steal! I'll join!
Kita-chan, you're already in the band.
What about you, Gotoh-san?
Any ideas?
What do I do? I wasn't even thinking!
W-Well...
H-Her eyes are so sparkly!
I feel the burden of expectation!
Um... Um...
I-If I don't say something, I... I...
Future
Society
Digital
Chiba
Memories
Passwords
Internet
Home Life
Outer Space
Old Books
New Stuff
Emotions
Part-
Time
Job
Dreams
Fukui
Laws
Identity
Life
Entertainment
Outer Space
Types of Fish
Nothing's coming to mind!
What do I... What do I...
Oh, Bocchi-chan can sit this one out.
She has a more important job:
writing lyrics for our original song!
We settled on it before, remember?
Ryo would write the music,
and you'd write the lyrics!
If you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
write the lyrics!
Wow! I can't wait to hear
your song, Ryo-senpai.
Have you written it already?
No.
I'll do it once I get inspiration.
I just can't wait!
Go for it, Ryo!
And Minister of Lyrics!
R-Right...
Gotoh-san, it's so cool that
you took on such a tough job!
C-Cool?!
W-Well, I can write lyrics
like nobody's business!
It's the super-easiest thing ever!
You get carried away so easily, Gotoh-san.
I'm gonna write the most band-like lyrics
and guarantee us a huge hit!
"Band-like"?
One Week Later
I couldn't think of anything!
Shake!
Change paws!
I failed to write a single lyric,
but I've perfected my signature...
Gotoh
Hitori Gotoh
Gocchi
Bocchi
This
one!
Hitori
Change, and pose!
Isn't it cool?
Why can't I get my priorities in order?!
Jimihen's amazing!
Futari!
I already spent five hours yesterday
editing video to escape reality.
Done.
I'm so stupid! I'm a paramecium!
Whatcha writin'?
No!
Here it is!
My lyrics notebook from middle school!
Lyrics
I've bought the ingredients for a voodoo doll
At 2:30 this morning I do the deed
5 inch nails  White Gown  Straw Doll
Mallet — All I need
The pain won't end in just seven days
Konk konk, konk konk  I drive it in
Konk konk, konk konk  It's 2 AM
Konk konk, konk konk  Here, all alone
Every day, alone, I curse you
Tremble in fear, la la la la...
5 inch nails          White Gown            Straw Doll
Mallet — All I need
The pain won't end in just seven days
A curse?
Ijichi
Energetic
Nice
Pretty
Gotoh
Social anxiety
Great at
compliments
Eats weeds
Doesn't talk
But not socially anxious
Yamada
Let's get organized.
Kita-san's gonna be singing this song.
Cheerful lyrics.
A seishun song, maybe?
Kit-aura!
I could easily write depressing lyrics,
of course...
Kit-aura!
Nobody wants that,
so I've gotta write something band-like,
with real Kit-aura!
Put yourself in the mind
of cheery person!
I'm an extrovert!
The woman who surfs in the pool at night!
The woman who claims the title Queen of Woot!
Woot! Woot! Woot!
Woot! Go! Go!
Let's get some vibes up in here!
Tequila shots in the house!
No! That's not a cheery person,
it's just a party animal!
No more shortcuts.
You must become Kita-san.
Come over now if you wanna go to Shibuya!
Everyone takes Isstaworthy pics right here!
They'll be launching fireworks in ten mins,
so let's take pictures together then!
I know an exorcist, if you need one...
It's n-n-n-not like that!
No Peeking
Okay, no seishun songs.
Let's try a song of encouragement.
I personally find status-quo-affirming
lyrics annoyingly irresponsible, but...
we're all here
sending you
Your dreams will come true
Believe in yourself
It's so shallow...
Any depressed person hearing this song
would just drop deeper into despair!
F-F-Forgive me!
Gotoh-san?
What's the matter now?
I-Isn't this an intervention
where you tear into me
I failed to write the lyrics I was assigned.
for failing to write lyrics
despite all the bragging I did?
That's perverse! No way!
Then why did you call us here?
I didn't think of it until now,
but there's one other really
band-like thing we can do!
Take ProPhos!
Promotional photos, she means.
Since Bocchi-chan isn't in
Kessoku Band's current ProPho.
C-Current?
Want to see?
We took it for our last concert.
I mean, since Kita-chan ditched us...
I'm sorry!
I've never seen such an awful ProPho.
So, because it's nice out today
and none of us have plans,
I figured we'd take a few ProPhos!
O-Outside?!
We don't have the money
to rent a studio, so...
Taking public pictures in Shimo-Kita
is too much to ask of a nerd like me!
We could do it in Starry
instead if you prefer,
but a ProPho is important
for conveying a band's direction
and the unique qualities of its members.
So we really need to give it
everything we have?
Precisely!
We need something that'll have impact,
whether it's in a club ad online,
a flyer, or a magazine!
What she said.
V-Very well.
I resign myself to this fate.
Resign yourself?
I declare this ProPho-scouting journey on!
Let's la go!
Yeah!
Yeah...
Stairs...
A fence...
With plants...
At the park...
I think we've covered all the bases
for broke band ProPhos...
Oh, and an evocative wall!
Milkus Water
I wish we'd brought our instruments.
G-Good point...
Having our instruments
might make us look cooler.
For you guys, maybe.
Only guitarists and bassists
look cool that way.
What about the poor drummer?
I'm stuck just holding up my drumsticks!
But that's cute.
Then let's swap instruments, just for today!
Nah, that's lame.
What about here?
Isn't it nice?
With all these posters up, it has
a real "Shimo-Kitazawa" vibe!
That used to be a CD shop I went to a lot.
Huh?
Lots of record shops and club venues
closing these days, yeah.
Shops that have been there for decades,
disappearing one by one...
I-I'm really sorry...
Ryo, you were just celebrating
that new book store.
Yeah. I love B&C.
Kita-chan, don't let Ryo jerk you around.
Ninety percent of the things she says
are more or less just for vibes.
But Senpai can jerk me around
any time she wants!
Um?
Oh, it's just Bocchi-chan.
U-Um...
I-I thought I saw a
n-nice-looking wall over there...
Hey, great work!
Taking it now!
We're definitely capturing everyone's
personalities, but it's not really band-like.
Isn't there a way to really
make it scream "band"?
As I am the quintessential musician,
you need only mimic my expression.
I'd love to know where you
get all that confidence...
But we can't go wrong doing what Senpai says!
Right, Gotoh-san?
Y-Yes...
A pair of yes-men, huh?
Fine, we'll do it.
Looks like we're at a funeral.
Yeah...
But Kita-chan looks cute in any pic we take!
Aw, no I don't!
Sure you do!
It's almost like you know what you're doing.
Oh, I guess it's because I upload pics
to Issta all the time!
See?
That's our Minister of Social Media!
Bocchi-chan's dying!
What's wrong, Gotoh-san? Stay with us!
Oh, no! She's flopping around like a fish!
I've never taken pictures
with friends before.
What do I do? Please, wake up!
Since... I never had friends before.
The only pictures I've taken
that weren't with family
were class pictures.
With those as my only proof of existence
for the past fifteen years...
Look at Bocchi-chan's weird face!
I wonder if there are any other
high school girls like me still around?
Perhaps I've become a rare species,
on par with the tsuchinoko?
I am... I am the tsuchinoko
of Shimo-Kitazawa.
Gotoh-san's saying the strangest things!
Nah, this is normal for her.
Noko-noko. Noko-noko.
Bocchi-chan, why don't you
start your own Isstagram?
What do you think, Minister?
Totally!
Let's become friends!
If we're going to be a band,
we should really have
individual member accounts!
Gotoh-san?!
If I were to get an account...
Someone with self-esteem so bad
she's already trying to form a band
to get popular despite
total social ineptitude...
If s-someone like me were to
start an account like that...
You would witness the birth of...
The attention-whore monster!
Like my posts!
My video site is all I need.
Gotoh-san!
Bocchi-chan!
We won't push you to get on social media anymore!
Please come back to us!
You okay?
Y-Yes...
Okay, back to the ProPhos!
Nothing's really hitting the spot...
Hey, what about a jump pic?
Jump pic?
It's really photogenic, and it could
bring out everyone's personality!
Great idea! You're a genius, Kita-chan!
A wise man once said,
any anime where they jump in
the OP is a god-tier anime.
Would jumping in our ProPho
thus make us a god-tier band?
Where is she getting that from?
I'm not sure I followed your logic there...
But let's give it a try!
Five, four, three,
I c-can't even remember
the last time I jumped!
two, one!
Oh, I see Bocchi's undies.
Wow, that's one hell of a picture!
I'm sorry for putting something
so worthless in the picture.
Please delete it.
I was hoping for a cuter reaction there...
If I can't even jump properly, I'm...
Okay, let's try one more!
Awesome! It's got the band feel
and the seishun thing going!
Do you think I could get
a copy of that picture?
M-Me too!
Yeah, we're feeling band-like now!
I feel like we're one step closer
to becoming a popular band!
R-Right!
Kessoku Band is getting started for real!
Okay!
We'll have our concert in summer (TBD),
our demo CD sale (TBD),
our first album release in winter (TBD),
and become Shimo-Kitazawa's own
good vibes-iest vibes-band!
Sounds like there's a lot
still to be decided!
Good point!
We don't even have a song yet!
I t-totally forgot about the lyrics!
Of course, we've got Ryo and
Bocchi-chan on the case, so...
Hey, where's Ryo?
She must have disappeared.
What a total free spirit!
Anyway, thanks for coming today!
Dismissed!
The more time that passes,
Lyrics
the higher the lyrics bar seems to rise.
I-If I show them this and
they're mean to me...
O-Or worse, if they're
obviously humoring me, I...
M-Maybe I should show it to
someone and see how they react.
Ryo-san, maybe.
I don't think Ryo-san would ever humor me.
Ryo
a
It's a pleasure to make contact with you
This is Bocchi speaking
If you happen to still be in Shimo-Kita,
do you think you might be able to
consider having a look at my lyrics?
Read
She already read it!
I'm here, come by
Huh?
A t-trendy café!
Congratulations
on Opening
Congrats on opening
Congrats, La Chic
Congratulations, La Chic
I've never been to a real
restaurant by myself.
I can't even enter a convenience store
without psyching myself up in advance.
Congrats on opening
A-Am I allowed to just walk in?
How do people just walk into places?
How do they do it on TV and stuff?
Oh, I know!
Are ya winning, diners?
Oh, Bocchi.
Over here.
Th-This is awkward.
Come to think of it, I've never
been alone with Ryo-san before.
I don't even know much about her.
F-For that matter, why hasn't
she talked to me yet?
That was delicious.
She finished eating!
What do I do? Should I initiate?
But...
That photo shoot sure was fun, huh?!
Not really.
That could be the result!
Just show me the lyrics.
Oh, right.
Thank you.
No problem. Let's see.
Oh, ohh!
She's unusually flustered!
This is good.
I'm not sure I agree,
but for the band's sake...
Yes, it's a masterpiece.
Gotoh
Hitori Gotoh
Gocchi
Bocchi
This
one!
Hitori
Though personally I think one
is a bit childish for a band.
That's not the right page!
Are you personally satisfied
with these lyrics, Bocchi?
Oh, w-well...
I figured we should do something
really "hit band"-like...
Can't do it anymore
You say as you give up on moving forward
On a road that seems to go on forever
It feels like you'll never arrive anywhere
And that's got you worried, doesn't it?
But hey now, listen up
Don't forget you're not alone, that we're all here
We're sending you this cheer just as your heart's about to break
Your dreams will come true
Don't give up until the very end!
Believe in yourself the way you are
Believe in yourself and get walking again!
Glory awaits you ahead, I know it
For everyone around the world trying hard, Go for it!
Did I ever tell you?
I was in another band a long time ago.
Their lyrics were awkward,
but I liked how honest they were.
But, desperate for sales, they started
going in a more commercial direction.
I hated that. That's why I quit.
We had a little fight about it at the time.
And just as I was feeling sick
of the whole band thing...
Hey.
If you've got time,
will you play bass for me?
Why?
Because I love the way you play!
When Nijika said that to me, I decided
to give playing in a band another try.
Abandoning your uniqueness
is equivalent to dying.
Ryo-san?
So don't write generic lyrics
based on other concerns.
Write what you want to write.
B-But if I do that, I'll write bitter,
social-outcast lyrics—
But won't it be hilarious
if a normie sings that?
I spend my days cursing you losers!
Bringing a wide variety of individuals
together into one sound...
That's the color that Kessoku Band will have.
Ryo-san is actually a considerate person.
Let's get out of here.
R-Right!
Oh, Ryo-san...
The check...
Sorry, I'm broke. Treat me?
Wh-What?
B-But you're the one who invited me...
I just couldn't take another
day of eating weeds.
You're still doing that?!
And this shop just opened,
and I wanted to eat here so bad...
Please, treat me?
I t-take back what I said!
I really am sorry.
I'll pay you back next month.
N-No need to rush...
U-Um...
I-I'm going to try my best!
Sure. Can't wait to see it.
U-Um...
I f-finished the lyrics...
H-Here.
Gotoh-san, are you all right? You look tired.
I'm fine.
I've just been so focused on the lyrics,
I c-completely forgot to sleep...
Wow!
Let's have a look!
I can't wait to see the
fruits of your labors!
It m-might be... too much of a downer.
It certainly is a downer.
Ryo-senpai!
But it's very Bocchi.
It might not connect with too many people,
but those it does, it'll hit deeply.
Where'd this friendship come from?!
But these lyrics really are
super great, Bocchi-chan!
I love this phrase here!
Same.
I m-managed to figure out the lyrics.
I'm going to do my best...
I hope the band can
stay together forever...
and I can get lots of
pictures with everyone.
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can’t beat that feeling
of being loved, it’s true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It’s time to take that step
Though there’s nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It’s time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I’ve been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I’m going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#05 Flightless Fish
Watch it.