Twenty more minutes...
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#02 See You Tomorrow
Several Days Earlier
Yesterday, Nijika-chan said...
Hi there!
Thanks for
everything today!
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
Hello thank you
GRATITUDE
Let's have a talk about our
future as a band! Meetup
at Starry tomorrow, okay?
Hi there!
Thanks for
everything today!
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
Let's have a talk about our future as a band!
Meetup at Starry tomorrow, okay?
The joy of getting LOINE messages
from someone who wasn't a relative
got me this far, but...
If I walk in there looking
like the hick I am,
they'll all look at me
like I don't belong there...
I made it in last time because
I was with Nijika-chan, but...
I wonder if anyone's there?
I wish I had someone to go in with.
Five minutes.
I'll wait five minutes, then go in.
No, ten...
Fifteen.
I'll totally go in after fifteen.
What's she doing?
Bo—
Wait.
I wanna watch a little longer.
Could you please stop enjoying this?
Okay!
I hereby declare the first Kessoku Band
members' meeting... open!
Round of applause!
Clappy clappy clap clap clap!
Now, let's see...
Oh, wait. We barely know each other,
so I dunno what to talk about!
She just admitted it!
I brought this for just such an occasion.
Bungee Jumping
Nice one!
I don't think I like the looks of this...
There!
What'll she roll? What'll she roll?
Dun-dun-dun-dun-dun...
Talk about School
Talk about school!
TAS for short!
Talk about School
Proceed.
Do not spill drinks! You may be liable for damages caused.
Um... Wait, don't you both
go to the same school...
Talk about School
Yeah, Shima High!
We chose it 'cause it's close to home.
Oh, so you live in Shimo-Kitazawa...
Huh? Bocchi-chan, don't you go to Shuka High?
Shouldn't you live around here too?
No, I live out-of-prefecture.
Two-hour commute each way.
Two hours?!
Why?
I wanted a high school
where nobody knew my past.
Okay, enough TAS!
S-Sorry...
I spend most of my time at school alone,
so I don't have any f-fun
stories to contribute...
Hey, it's okay!
Ryo doesn't have many friends either.
Yeah, just Nijika.
Tha-thump.
Ryo-san is just like me...
Loneliness Hill
On days off, she does urban exploration
and visits second-hand clothing shops...
No, she's not...
Ryo-san likes being alone!
Someone with social anxiety could never
enter a clothing shop on her own!
Lonely
The gap between the lonely and the loner
is too deep and vast to ever be traversed!
Loner
I nearly fell into the trap.
Bocchi-chan, let's enjoy the conversation!
Talk about Favorite Music
Next up, we'll talk about our favorite music!
For short...
TAFM!
T-TAFM...
I like Japanese punk, like mellow core.
I like techno kayo,
and lately I've been checking
the Saudi Arabian charts—
True stuff only, please!
That is true.
Bocchi-chan?
Oh, um...
I like any songs that don't
trigger my seishun complex.
"Seishun complex"?
Allow me to explain!
Guitar Man's Easy-to-Learn Hitori Classes
Seishun Complex Edition
Songs that trigger Hitori's seishun complex
Guitar Man's Easy-to-Learn Hitori Classes
Seishun Complex Edition
are glitter-coated upbeat songs
that include words like
"summer," "blue sea,"
"fireworks," "puppy love,"
and other things irrelevant to
her personal school experience!
Such words plunge me into a deep melancholy.
Hey, Bocchi-chan?
By the same token,
you love bands that write about the
bleakness of their high school years, right?
Hey...
Oh, yeah!
But sometimes I find out a band I love
was super popular in school,
and they suddenly feel
like strangers to me...
Hey, please! Come back to our planet, please!
Rock resonates as the music
of the perpetual underdog.
Is it really rock if it's
sung by life's winners?
I'm trying to establish some ties, here!
Since we're named after zip ties.
Talk about the Concert
Um...
Our first concert was instrumentals only,
but I'd like to have vocals next time.
Oh, do you?
The guitarist who ran off was
gonna be our singer, but...
Where'd she even go, anyway?
The runaway guitarist...
Maybe she's socially anxious like me.
No, there's no way!
If you're really socially anxious,
you can't even run away!
We've gotta find a new vocalist.
I can't sing for squat, myself.
Bocchi-chan, can you—
Yeah... Figured.
Um... Wh-What about Ryo-san?
Sob
If I were to serve as frontman,
I'd overwhelm the band and crush it.
Sob
Where do you get that
wellspring of confidence?
Sob
I'm so jealous.
I'd like a little of that
confidence for myself...
I know!
Let's find a vocalist and write a song!
Ryo can write the music,
and if you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
Me?!
Well? Great idea, huh?
The nine years of lunch breaks
I spent in school libraries...
Was it all in preparation for this moment?
So, what will you do, Nijika?
Go!
Next, talk about quotas!
Just shamelessly dodged that one, eh?
Um... What are quotas?
The concert we did yesterday
is called a "booked concert."
It's where the club assigns
the band a ticket quota
to make sure enough people come.
Your quota is ten tickets!
Anything sold over the quota gets
split between the club and the band...
But if they can't bring in
enough to meet the quota,
the band has to pay the rest out of pocket.
So until you get popular, it's a money pit.
That's very concise!
A bunch of my friends came
to yesterday's concert,
so we managed to meet our quota, but...
After that performance,
they likely won't be back.
You said it!
And Ryo's got no friends,
so she'll be no help...
Bocchi-chan, do you—
Oh, sorry! Forget what I said.
Just please lose the dead fish stare!
I've got plenty of imaginary friends, but...
You rock, Hitori-chan!
Living national treasure!
Anyway, since we'll need tens of thousands
of yen before our next concert,
let's get jobs to cover
the quota and equipment!
Okay.
Jobs?!
That's the loudest I've ever heard you.
No.
I don't want to work. Too scary!
Society is too scary!
A piggy bank?
M-My mom was saving up for my wedding...
But you can have it.
Just... Please, no job...
Don't make us the bad guys here!
Thanks, we'll take good care of—
We're not taking it!
We can't take money that
means that much to you!
But...
I don't wanna work!
Because...
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
It'd totally be like that...
Not this cashier who can't even make eye contact lmaoooooooooooooo
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
And then that...
Breaking
Defendant Hitori Gotoh's First Trial
For the crime of creeping out the customers,
we seek the death penalty!
Okay, here comes the ruling...
Death!
And then that!
...cchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan!
You weren't listening, were you?
S-Sorry!
Wh-What were you saying?
You should work here with us.
Here?
What?!
You won't have to be scared
if you're with me and Ryo!
Talk about Quotas
It's a homey and harmonious place to work.
We can serve drinks, and clean,
and see all kinds of bands!
Don't wanna work... Don't wanna work...
Well? What do you think?
Say no, girl!
Say no!
You have to say no!
I'll dwu mwy bwest...
Really? Thanks so much!
Sorry, girl...
The job'll be more fun if we're all together!
It wouldn't be social anxiety
if we had the courage to say no.
I'll manage the band's funds, then.
Um... Wouldn't it be better
to have Ryo-san do that?
What's that supposed to mean?!
Listen, Bocchi-chan.
Believe it or not,
Ryo's a very irresponsible spender.
Her family's rich and she
gets a huge allowance,
but she blows it all on instruments,
so she's constantly broke!
Blush.
What part of that did you
take as a compliment?
Anyway, let's work hard
so we can play live again soon!
Then we'll make our major
debut in high school!
We start work next week!
Come straight here after school!
Bocchi. Bye-bye.
R-Right...
And that first day of work is tomorrow.
I've been in here for thirty minutes now.
I'm bound to catch a cold, right?
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
I'll work hard at everything except the job.
Mom! Sis is drowning!
Catch a cold! Catch a cold!
Catch a cold!
Curse this good health of mine...
Then I'll just have to fake—
Nijika-chan?
Morning!
First day of work, right?
I know you're nervous,
but we'll be there for you!
Let's work hard together!
No fair being so nice while
I'm trying to blow off work...
You've made me realize the
foolish error of my ways.
For making an honest woman out of me,
you have my boundless gratitude.
What is she talking about?
I'm here.
Do it, Bocchi!
Tickets don't go on sale until five o'clock.
We're still getting ready here.
She works here?!
She thinks I'm up to no good...
I've got to clear this up!
C-C-C-C-C-Calm down...
You're the one who needs to calm down.
So you're the new part-timer?
You should've just said so.
S-S-S-S-Sorry!
I'm the manager here. Nice to meet you.
V-Very nice to meet you...
The manager's scary.
I can't handle people like her.
Nijika-chan, come here quick!
Hey, you're the guitarist
who played in the box.
Wasn't it... Mango Kamen?
A new nickname?
I like you, Manager!
I-I'm Mango Kamen!
That is not her name!
Don't go giving her weird nicknames, Sis!
Sis?!
You're Nijika-chan's sister?
I told you before.
When you first came to Starry, remember?
The club we're gonna play at
is called Starry.
My big sister's the manager there.
Actually, our family lives
in the apartments above it.
My heart was pounding so loud
that I didn't hear her.
R-R-R-Really?
That means you don't have to be so nervous.
Right, Sis?
Call me "Manager" here.
And keep our work and private
relationships separate.
Don't scare her like that!
Good Kid
Apple 100
Okaka
Okay, let's clear the tables first.
When that's done, we'll wipe them all down...
Huh? Where's Bocchi-chan?
Sorry. I needed a breather
in a dark, cramped place.
You need a breather already?!
Here, Bocchi-chan, come over
and learn the drinks.
Tonic water comes out of here,
and beer comes out of this dispenser.
The cocktails are on the shelf behind...
I-I'll never remember it all!
Too fast!
I just... mummummmmm...
I'll have to infuse the knowledge
into me through song!
Where did that come from?!
Cocktails are in the rightmost shelf!
You're scaring me!
Tequila!
They seem fun.
I'm glad you're learning the drinks,
Vodka!
but why don't you set the guitar down?
Kahlua!
Rum!
Hey, are you listening?
Weird... She seemed kind of
crappy at the concert, but...
You're not, are you?!
She's good.
You're seriously scaring me!
Nijika's trying so hard to stop her,
I don't think she realizes it...
P-Please! Come back to us!
Hitori-chan!
But I recognize that sound from somewhere.
Get to work!
Why me?!
For drink service, just pour the
drinks they order and hand them over.
R-Right...
They can pay 500 yen
on top of the ticket price
to get a drink ticket.
500 yen per drink?
And why a drink ticket system?
Stop staring like it's totally alien to you.
Clubs like this are actually
considered restaurants.
I don't know all the details,
but apparently it's super hard to get a
business license to run just a concert venue.
I... I see!
So we offer drinks
and operate like a restaurant.
Are you listening?
W-Working at a restaurant is advanced stuff!
I can't believe I cleared that bar so soon!
Is this... personal growth?!
Loneliness Hill
Hey, customers already!
We're about to be busy, Bocchi-chan!
Loneliness Hill
What?
Wait... Customer service already?!
What do I say?!
"Thank you for your royal parentage..."
That's not it!
J-Just give me a practice run, please!
N-No, wait! Stop it!
Thanks for coming!
She closed up!
Excuse me! One cola, please!
Coming!
Bocchi-chan, cola!
Coming up!
I'll have a ginger ale.
Bocchi-chan, show some
respect for the customers!
B-B-But I'm not ready!
We're losing the club's inherent darkness.
One oolong and one highball!
Where's the bathroom?
Down the hall to your right,
door on the left!
I experienced no personal growth whatsoever.
Bocchi-chan, look!
Here they are!
Hey, there! We're Alexandism!
Our second album goes on sale today,
They're pretty good, y'know?
so we're back to doing concerts,
It's a good time to relax.
but we hope you all bought it!
Once the performances start,
we'll have time to kill.
Thanks!
Right...
Good work.
Good work!
We tried to make every single
song better than our first album,
Don't you have to sell tickets?
Manager stepped in for me.
All of today's bands are really popular,
and if you haven't bought it yet,
we're about to play some of those songs,
so she told me to watch and learn.
That's my sister for you.
so if you like them, please buy the album!
She's a tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun...
And there's something I want
to tell you guys first.
...dere. You know?
Excessive tsun.
The crowd rocked pretty
hard at our last concert!
S-S-Sorry...
Not only did I fail to help you,
So after it was over, a guy came up
and offered up his card.
I couldn't even make eye
contact with the customers.
Want this?
And we were so nervous. "Is this time
for our major debut?" we thought.
Sorry it's not for mangos.
No, thank you.
But it would look pretty lame to let it show,
You're doing fine!
so after a beat we just said,
"Hello, welcome."
It's your first day. You'll get used to it!
"Welcome?"
Habits can be scary, huh?
Wh-Why are you so nice to a
sub-water-flea like me?
The words that came out of my mouth
were the words I've said a million
times at my part time job.
You know...
According to the guy who gave us his card,
I really like this club.
he wanted to listen to the band
on after us today, Tidaman,
But here and reception are the only places
club staff interact with the customers,
but we don't get along with them,
and we really wanna outshine them,
so I want to do my best to make
other people like it, too.
so we hope you listen to Alexandism too!
I'm s-s-sorry.
I w-worked so badly at a place
that means so much to you...
No, no.
Now, let me introduce the band!
That's not what I meant.
Always eating curry before a concert, with his
own way of doing things... on bass, Matsuda!
I meant I want you to like
this club too, Bocchi-chan.
And the normal guy who always
has our backs... on drums, Rei!
I want us to have fun working,
and to have fun playing.
He's got so many effects pedals he barely has
room on stage to stand... on guitar, Koichi!
Together.
And on guitar and vocals, without
much to recommend him... me!
'Course, I also hope you'll be able to speak
to customers with a smile some day, too...
Tsuyoshi!
Let's do this!
It's starting, Bocchi-chan!
The whole place is united.
The customers and the performers
are all enjoying themselves.
Meanwhile, at my concert...
The customers paid 2,000 yen
to see that, didn't they?
If I stay the way I am,
I'm gonna give them the same listless
concert next time too, aren't I?
I want to make the effort to change,
even if only gradually,
and enjoy it with the rest of them.
Excuse me!
Orange juice.
C-Coming up...
Look the customer in the eye. Interact.
Smile!
Look her in the eye!
Interact!
H-Here you are.
Bocchi-chan! Your eyes! Your eyes!
Thanks!
Wow, that was nerve-wracking!
But great job!
You kept your head above the counter
and talked to her!
I did my best!
Yeah!
Having you here will make my memories
of today's concert even more fun.
And you've taken a step forward.
A step...
A step.
A step?!
It feels like I took a thousand, though!
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Good work today.
Take care getting home.
Bye-bye.
Th-Thank you for having me.
Not leaving, Ryo?
Staying a little while first.
Bocchi-chan!
Y-Yes?!
See you later!
Y-Yes, s-s-s-see you tomorrow!
It's over!
I made it through an entire day somehow!
This work thing isn't as hard
as I thought it would be!
I'll do my best again tomorrow!
Achoo!
Eh?
Bocchi worked hard, huh?
Yeah.
And she managed to say "see you tomorrow!"
I'm glad we formed this band.
Oh, right!
Let's send a LOINE message to Bocchi-chan.
I'll say, "Let's keep it up tomorrow!"
Nijika
You have a message
She's got an awful fever.
Dear, prepare a cold compress, would you?
Does she need a trip to the hospital?
N-Now I get the fever...
Now that we've got Bocchi-chan on board...
All that's left...
is to find a new vocalist!
Who's this one for?
Me, me! It's me, it's me!
The tune that plays when my loneliness
and the pedal are stepped on
Tracks down my cheeks over and over again
The pounding of my loneliness
Is joined by the rhythm of the snare drum
To create a solid pulse
Someone, please remove
the distortion on my heart
And take a look inside me
Nobody can get inside my heart
But it's the kind of night
when I hope someone will
Distortion it's Motion
Once it starts, there's no stopping it
Limits can be overwritten with experience
Isn't that right?
Distortion is always like that
My heart takes off, outpacing my left brain
Toward where you are
An escort to the next note
Distortion on my day-to-day anguish
The chord I play when I'm alone at night
Is it the same for you?
I spent all those days chasing my ideal image
Play an F chord with distortion
So loud that the needle swings off the scale
#3  Be Right There
Watch it!