Gotoh
The Departure of Flamingos from Enoshima
Penguins appear in Tama River!
They're okay in freshwater?
Recruiting part-time!
A melancholy Monday has arrived.
Feels good to be over your cold, huh?
Y-Yeah...
Or are you happy your cold
let you miss school a few days?
Not at all.
How come?
You always say you wanna stay home...
I don't like going to school,
but for someone like me,
even one day of failing to attend class
puts me in risk of being
forgotten by my classmates.
Guess you're a real pain
in your own ass, Sis!
Oh, and Mom says it's time to eat!
Yes, it's true.
I could burst from the sheer volume
of nuisance I inflict upon myself.
But wait a minute.
I joined a band, and I'm
working part-time at a club!
Perhaps I've graduated from my introversion!
Yes!
I'll take my guitar to school again.
Someone's bound to talk to me this time!
Yep. Putting the onus on
others fails once again.
Hey, did you watch the latest Oto-Station?
I did did!
You can stream BAKWIMPS again!
I've been listening to them
so much since yesterday,
they're still playing in my head!
Uh-oh!
Band talk!
What's up, Gotoh-san?
You hardly ever talk to anyone!
All my preparation assumed
others would approach me first,
so I don't know how
to start a conversation...
I forgot.
In that short a time?!
It's lunchtime!
This is for the best.
If I'd managed to talk to them,
right about now...
Barging into our convo like that...
Was she listening in the
whole time or something?!
I didn't know she was such a creep!
That's definitely how it'd be!
I'll never rise above my station again.
I'll live under the radar forever!
Thank you for the meal.
Still... A quiet place like this
is just perfect for lunch.
I'm glad I found a nice spot.
It's awkward eating all alone
in the classroom.
And once I become a popular guitarist,
I'll go on Oto-Station and say...
What were you like in high school?
I didn't have any friends back then.
I often ate lunch in a dark corner
filled with desks and janitorial supplies.
I can awe people with how much
I've changed! Y'know how it is...
Karaoke was so much fun the other day!
People!
Kita-chan's such a great singer.
I heard she played guitar in a band before she quit.
Kids, don't try this at home!
Wow! Now that's musical talent!
Band?
Come to think of it, Nijika-chan was talking
about wanting a new guitar-slash-vocalist...
Since my cold kept me from
working for a few days,
I must find a guitar-slash-vocalist
to prove my commitment to Kessoku Band!
Kessoku Band
Now Recruiting Guitar/Vocalist
Even newbies can come and learn!
Please!!
Please contact STARRY staff
But the thought of going up
to a total stranger...
Kita-chan!
Heya!
I'm super sorry, but I have
a huge favor to ask...
What kind of girl is she?
What is it?
Would you mind pitching in at
our basketball game next week?
She's pretty!
Hey, sure thing!
She's super nice!
Kids, don't try this at home!
Maybe I'll land a three-pointer!
She's pretty, and athletic, and popular,
Awesome! Thanks!
and she plays the guitar...
I'm supposed to issue an
invitation to someone like her?!
In fact, my identity...
My entire identity is crumbling!
Identity
Pwip.
What was that sound?
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#3 Be Right There
I worked up the courage
to arrive at her classroom,
but my mental fortitude lags behind...
You're Gotoh-san from Class 2, right?
Sh-She knows my n—
Are you looking for someone in here?
S-Say it, Hitori!
Band Is Looking For
A Guitar/Vocalist
"My band is looking for a guitar-slash-
vocalist. Would you be interested?"
Ba! Gui! Vo!
Ba
Gui
Vo
She became a human beatbox!
Er...
Bam-chika-boom-chika...
bam-chika-boom-chika...
I... I'm so sorry!
W-Wait!
Two more additions to
my dark past in one day.
Lend me your ears.
This is my new song: Double Dark Past,
Bocchi Acoustic Version.
Melancholy days, multiplying traumas
Wanna ditch this negative legacy I carry...
The memories bring soft,
secret tears to my eyes
Mourning my past, so many dark mornings
Wishing, someday,
to just laugh it all away...
Begone, memories...
That was awesome!
K-Kita-san?!
How long have you...
I got so worried when you ran off like that,
but that was incredible!
You're amazing at guitar, Gotoh-san!
That song you were playing
had me totally enraptured!
She's saying nice things about me!
What a nice person!
Are you in a band?
K-Kind of...
Hey, can you play other stuff? I wanna hear!
Kit-aura
The extrovert aura... It's so powerful,
I can't look straight at her!
Oh, and you were trying to talk
to someone earlier, right?
Th-This is my chance to invite her!
W-Well, our band is actually
looking for a guitar-slash-vocalist,
and I heard you played guitar, so...
Oh, so that's why.
H-Huh?
I'm sorry, Gotoh-san.
I can't join your band.
O-Oh, but...
I'm kind of a nerd, but the others are cool!
Oh, it's not a problem with you or anything.
They're holding a barbecue next weekend!
Meat!
They host a sports meet every six months!
They party in limousines after every gig!
This is the life!
They do so much cool stuff!
I don't want a band that parties that hard...
And... And...
The truth is, I can't
actually play guitar at all.
I was in another band not long ago.
I lied when I joined because
I wanted to get close to my senpai.
But the whole thing was just
beyond me, so I ran away.
Beyond you?
Yeah.
There's more to playing than just
this strum-strum stuff, right?
I'd figured this wooden stick part
was just for decoration!
It's way too hard for someone
to learn on their own.
"Major chords"? "Minor"?
What is this, baseball?
Her non-comprehension
is on a whole other level!
Did someone teach you to play, Gotoh-san?
N-No, I mostly taught myself...
What?! Really? That's awesome!
It's not that great...
I know! Will you teach me to play, Gotoh-san?
You can be my teacher!
You're so brilliant, I just know
you'll get me through it!
Oh, shucks...
I want to learn to play properly,
go back to my old band, and apologize!
So, when can you teach me?
After class, maybe?
I-I've got a job at a club after class...
Then after work, maybe?!
Is there a studio next door?
We can do it there!
Oh... Oh...
V-Very well.
Really? Thanks!
Why am I so stupid?! Say no, girl!
Can we start right away?
C-Certainly...
Crap, crap, crap, crap, crap!
I've gotta get the girls
to act like party people!
It's from Bocchi-chan.
I'm sorry!
Please come to work today blaring EDM and
dancing around with energy drinks on hand!
What in the world?
Beats me.
Oh... You work in Shimo-Kitazawa?
Y-You've been?
My last band was in Shimo-Kita,
and its members lived in the area, so...
R-Really?
Hang on!
You can't walk behind me!
I don't know the way!
I'm sorry. I'm still not
used to being here...
I'm so embarrassed!
I'm the one embarrassed here!
W-We're almost there.
It's a place called Starry.
Nijika-chan and Ryo-san
will already be there...
I'm sorry. I can't go.
How come?
I'm sorry.
I can't tell you why,
but that's the one place I can't go!
And you can never tell those people I was h—
Bocchi-chan!
Your instructions were super weird,
but I bought energy drinks like you asked!
The runaway guitarist!
Runaway... guitarist?
Kita-chan, what are you doing here?
W-W-Well, I...
Eh?
Forgive my prior discourtesy!
I'll do anything to make up for it!
I give you permission to rough me up good!
Shh! You're gonna give people the wrong idea!
What?
So you couldn't play guitar, Kita-chan?
Nope.
And that's why you always ditched practice?
Yeah...
Poor Kita-san seems so uncomfortable...
I-If only I could think of
something nice to say.
We were worried when we didn't hear from you.
Ryo-san, so smooth!
Senpai!
I assumed you were dead, so I've been
lighting incense for you every day.
RIP.
That's a pretty wild assumption...
Um... You aren't angry?
I sorta blame ourselves
for not catching on sooner.
Besides...
We managed to work it out anyway!
S-Still, I feel too awful!
Please, let me make it up to you!
I'm not sure how...
How about you help out today at the club?
It's gonna be a busy night.
Th-That can't be enough...
No, that'd be a huge help!
Please join us!
If you'd like...
I'm so glad they worked it out...
So, go over there and get changed.
Changed?
Why does Manager have that outfit?
She's pretty darn good for a fill-in worker.
Yeah, Kita-chan knows what she's doing!
Sh-She really does!
She'll give me extra time to slack off.
I'll take it out of your pay.
You smell good, Kita-san.
Thank you so much!
Maybe it's the shampoo? It's my favorite!
Sh-She's never said my name before!
You're pretty outgoing,
Kita-chan. Wanna try reception?
I'll teach you!
Okay!
And the job they've never trusted me with!
500 yen for a drink ticket!
What band did you come to see today?
Take a flyer, if you like!
Say, not bad at all!
I love interacting with people!
Ryo always handles reception,
but her dead eyes are kind of a problem...
And her poker face can be scary.
Ryo-senpai looks fine just the way she is!
Trash
Recyclables
Kita Kita
Bocchi. What are you doing down there?
Losing my identity.
Now, lend me your ears. This is...
"The Elegy of the Part-Time Worker Who Lost
Her Identity to the Just-Arrived Newbie."
Thanks for watching,
everyone!
Illustration by Aki Hamaji
We haven't known each other long,
but I enjoyed the precious
time we spent together.
Bocchi-chan! Bocchi-chan!
Teach Kita-chan how to do the drinks!
R-Right!
Now's my chance to restore my good name!
I can't do it!
I get nervous when I'm being watched!
Sploosh
Splooosh
Sploooosh
Splooooosh
Sploooooosh
You okay?
I think I get the idea,
so you can rest a while.
Please forgive my arrogance...
I'm just glad you
weren't seriously hurt.
Th-Thank yo...
What?
Her fingertips...
Gotoh-san, what made you want to join a band?
It's an indoor activity where
you can be flashy and cool...
And I wanna be popular...
My motives are excessively impure!
W-World peace... I want to
work toward world peace.
How conscientious!
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Kessoku Band
Now Recruiting Guitar/Vocalist
Even newbies can come and learn!
Please!!
Please contact STARRY staff
Here's your cola!
Um, so the senpai you
wanted to get closer to...
Yeah.
It's Ryo-senpai.
Here ya go.
Unlike you, I have very impure motives.
I saw Senpai playing on the street,
and fell head-over-heels for her.
Ryo-san was in another band, too?
Her above-it-all attitude, her unisex look...
It all makes me squee!
"Squee"?
And she just looks so right
holding an instrument!
Oh, I know what you mean!
Wh-When I hold mine, it looks more
like the instrument's holding me.
Right? You end up like
an appendage to the instrument.
I wonder how that happens?
It's like we're best
buddies all of a sudden...
That's one thing about Ryo-senpai that—
Um, can I get a cassis orange?
Right! Coming right up!
Bye-bye, buddies!
I'll know my place next time...
After I heard her play,
I followed Ryo-san's activities for a while,
and she dropped out of her
last band pretty suddenly.
H-Huh...
Then I found out she was
recruiting for Kessoku Band,
and without thinking, I said I'd do it.
S-Such initiative! Extroversion abounds!
A band is like your second family, you know?
Family?
Yeah, you spend more time with them
than with your actual family,
and you're all chasing the same dream...
It's a mysterious relationship,
closer than friends or significant others.
I've never done clubs or anything similar,
so I've always wanted to be part of that.
I get you.
I always wanted it too...
Yes... I wanted to join Kessoku Band
and become Senpai's girl!
So much deeper and more
intimate than friendship!
Wait. Is Kita-san kind of not-okay?
But that's all the more reason
I can't join the band now.
I flaked out once already.
I'm too irresponsible.
I don't deserve to be in the band.
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Okay, good work, all. Feel free to head home.
Thanks for having us!
Thank you for having us...
Thanks for everything today.
Good luck with your band!
I'll keep rooting for you!
Goodbye!
H-Hey...
Bocchi-chan?!
Are you all right, Gotoh-san?
You're not still worried about me, are you?
I'm sorry.
Like I said before,
I can't join Kessoku Band.
I can't play guitar,
and I already flaked out once...
I... I... I...
I also ran away before the concert.
I hid in a trash can, and...
A-A-And also...
Let's get you up, Bocchi-chan.
One, two...
Here we go!
K-Kita-san, your left hand...
Y-You had calluses on your fingertips.
I... I th-think...
You'd have to be practicing
the guitar pretty hard for that.
Y-Yeah!
Kita-chan, we'd love to have you
rocking out with us in Kessoku Band!
Why would you let me...
Because if you hadn't flaked out,
we'd never have met Bocchi-chan!
Y-Yeah!
I've always wanted to have a band,
so I get how it feels intimidating
and aspirational at the same time.
S-So do I!
S-Sorry. That came out
louder than I expected.
You'd be happy to have her too, right, Ryo?
I'll only have to pay one-quarter
of the studio and quota fees.
Be a little less honest, would you?
I can be part of Senpai's quota!
So much for that healthy
moving-on thing, I guess...
But I still can't play the guitar...
That's okay!
Bocchi-chan will teach you!
Eh?
Yeah, yeah.
Ehh?
You will?
Y-Yes!
I can't exactly turn her down now!
Thank you.
I'll work really hard to
play guitar in Kessoku Band!
Oh, but you should probably give up
that party lifestyle of yours...
You're dancing like mad
every night, right?
Where'd you hear that?!
I'm glad it's all mended.
It came out like a mess, but I'm glad
I stopped Kita-san from leaving.
I worked really hard!
Well, I gotta head out now...
Bocchi-chan, don't go!
You're today's MVP!
You're the reason we're back together.
Thank you, Gotoh-san!
Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me   Praise me
Gosh, well, it was nothing,
really, honestly...
It obviously wasn't nothing for you.
Gotoh-san wears her heart on her sleeve.
But I practiced for so long, and yet
I never really learned how to play guitar.
It just made this quiet 'bum-bum' sound.
Y-You're sure it wasn't a bass?
Hey, I'm not that ignorant!
A bass has four strings, right?
See? It's got the full six strings!
S-Some do have six strings...
That's a six-string bass.
K-Kita-san!
It cost me two years'
advance allowance from my dad,
not to mention my New Year's money...
Kita-chan!
And so, Kessoku Band officially
had all their members.
No more!
I hereby quit the guitar!
What? Are we breaking up already?
Is this one defective too?
Did I get another bass?
N-No, that's definitely a guitar...
I'm sorry I whine so much.
I know you're giving up your time after
class and during lunch to teach me...
H-Hey, it's not...
With Ryo-senpai lending me this guitar,
and everyone helping... I have to do my best.
B-But I really am glad... that Ryo-san
b-bought that bass off of you...
Yeah.
But when she gave me the money...
This is the last of my money,
so I'll be eating weeds from now on.
That was a joke, right?
She might have been serious!
Oh, come on...
This one's so hard to hold.
The F chord is too hard!
That takes me back.
I was this way at the start, too.
Ryo-senpai! Hello...
You guys're here early.
Sh-She really is eating weeds!
Senpai's so wild!
The tune that plays when my loneliness
and the pedal are stepped on
Tracks down my cheeks over and over again
The pounding of my loneliness
Is joined by the rhythm of the snare drum
To create a solid pulse
Someone, please remove
the distortion on my heart
And take a look inside me
Nobody can get inside my heart
But it's the kind of night
when I hope someone will
Distortion it's Motion
Once it starts, there's no stopping it
Limits can be overwritten with experience
Isn't that right?
Distortion is always like that
My heart takes off, outpacing my left brain
Toward where you are
An escort to the next note
Distortion on my day-to-day anguish
The chord I play when I'm alone at night
Is it the same for you?
I spent all those days chasing my ideal image
Play an F chord with distortion
So loud that the needle swings off the scale
#4  Jumping Girl(s)
Watch it!