Emergency! Emergency!
The band we had scheduled can't perform!
Are you kidding?!
How will we find a replacement?
Perhaps I could be of some assistance?
Y-You're...
I forget the name,
but the girl from Class 2—
The name's Gotoh.
Gotoh-sama!
Hold me!
You're a living national treasure!
Gotoh! Gotoh!
...six votes for a haunted house,
and two votes for a candy shop.
How long have I been out?
I think I was in homeroom, and they started
talking about festival project ideas...
It's no use.
Everything after the word
"unity" came up is a blank.
Okay! So by majority vote,
Class 2's project will be
a maid and butler cafe!
We'll have to get lots of maid uniforms!
M-Maid?
Since all the girls'll be wearing them!
All the girls?!
Does that include... me?
N-No way!
Too far outside my skill set!
Grave Cafe
This way to the afterlife
Maybe if it was a grave cafe...
A-Afterlife for two...
Souvenirs from the grave available...
Crud, that was close.
I almost spaced out again.
And if anyone wants to perform on the
second day of the culture festival,
• Theater Play
• Whack-A-Mole
• Yoyo
• Stamp Rally
• Photo Booth
• Hot Dogs
• Maid/Butler Cafe
• Haunted House
• Candy Shop
make sure you put one of these forms in
the box in front of the student council room.
Perform on-stage as a band...
I never got to do it in middle school.
But I daydreamed about it a thousand times,
so same thing, right?
You feelin' the hype, arena?
Besides, I play in real venues now!
My band's not for fun and games!
It's serious business!
If someone from our class played,
they'd be the coolest person ever!
Totally!
How'd I end up at the student council room?!
What's this piece of paper?
Stage Performance Application
Please Circle Desired Day
10/1  •  10/2
Band Performance
Kessoku Band
Hitori Gotoh
A band performance application...
Kessoku Band...
Who wrote all this?!
What? Hitori Gotoh wrote it?!
I'm a professional guitarist now!
Begone, lust for culture festival attention!
Focus on your band's career!
Good... the lust is fading.
What was that?
Teacher! Someone's collapsed out here!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#10 After Dark
An unfamiliar ceiling.
Hey, you're awake?
How are you feeling?
I'm f-fine.
I heard you collapsed, so I got worried.
S-Sorry.
What's the matter?
N-Nothing...
Wh-What do I do?
If I tell Kita-san, she'll get
all excited, eyes sparkling,
and insist that we do it!
I m-must avoid that!
Th-Thank you for coming.
I-I'll head to work after a little more rest.
D-Don't worry about me.
But won't you be lonely?
I'll b-b-be fine!
Y-You've got plans with friends today, right?
Sure, but I can cancel them!
I'll b-b-be fine!
You're sure?
Well, just take it easy, okay?
I'd really like to perform,
but I've barely done a real concert,
so it's still really scary.
Although...
Now that I think about it,
all the performers in a high school
culture festival are amateurs.
I wonder what the vibe is like...
Y'all
(Hipster Kid)
What's up, y'all?
Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement  Class Unity  First Page of Youth  True Comrades  Friends to the End  Shining Bonds  Joyous Cheers  Classmate Encouragement
Ready to feel the hype?!
Yeah!
We're
We're gonna make one hell of a memory today!
gonna make
a memory
today!
Join me on this journey!
J
o
i
n
me!!
Nope. I'm so worn out,
I can't even watch the concert.
But a loner-type shining at the
culture festival is a classic trope!
So maybe I can do it too?!
Next up, Kessoku Band performs!
On drums, Nijika Ijichi
from Shimo-Kitazawa High!
Wah!  Squee!  So pretty!  So cute!  Look at me!  Waaah!  Wahhh!
Hi there!
And Ryo Yamada, from the same!
Mini-bow.
And on lead guitar, from Class 2... Um...
Oh, Gotoh-san!
And on guitar and vocals, from Class 5,
our school star, Kita-chan!
So cute!  Eee!  Squee!  Waaaaah!  Eee!  Eeee! Waaah!
It's Kita-chan!
We love you!
Thanks, guys!
Kita-chan!                    Kita-chan!
The fervor gap is too intense!
Yeah. Not happening.
I gotta know my place.
Good morning, Manager.
Uh, could you do some work?
If you're already on the fence,
I think you should do it.
These high school years will
be gone before you know it.
Yeah, maybe...
Not that I'd know, since I
barely cared about high school.
I dropped out!
I asked the wrong people.
I could never drag myself
out of bed in the morning!
Huh?
Bocchi-chan's talking to Sis?
That never happens.
She's waffling about her culture festival.
Culture festival?
She's trying to figure out if
Kessoku Band should perform there.
Performing at a culture festival?
Sounds awesome! Let's do it!
Um... But...
It's fun in a different way
from performing at a club.
Y-You've done it before, Nijika-chan?
Yeah, in middle school.
Same.
I played obscure songs and totally
bombed with the audience!
Why do you sound proud of that?
SMUGFACE
I've never played with Ryo
at a culture festival, though,
so I'd love to play at this one!
Really?
Well, we only recently formed Kessoku Band.
I'd like to play my original songs
somewhere other than here, too.
Plus, it's a great chance
to advertise ourselves!
But...
Don't you get expelled for playing
Disciplinary Notice
Class 1-2
Hitori Gotoh
Reason for Reprimand
For singing a song with extremely depressing lyrics
at a culture festival intended to hype people up,
the aforementioned is officially expelled
under article 50 of the school code.
something other than seishun rock
at a high school culture festival?
Of course not!
I get why Bocchi's scared, though.
There's a chance—a likelihood, rather—that
you'll be playing in front of a large crowd.
So you don't have to rush to a decision.
Ryo-san...
To be honest, I still have nightmares
about that concert I bombed.
So you were just acting strong earlier?
Either way, just make sure
you don't have any regrets, Bocchi-chan.
Wise words.
G-Got it.
I'll think it over.
Right, right!
Nijika-chan wants to play
at the culture festival too.
I bet it'd feel pretty darn good...
I...
I just can't do it!
I'm sorry, everyone.
I thought I could do it
yesterday, but I can't.
B-But Nijika-chan told me to make
sure I don't have any regrets,
and if I blow it, I don't think I could
make it through the rest of high school...
I'm already nervous
about playing in a club.
The thought of being
on stage at a festival...
Yeah, just not happening.
Skyrocketing to fame!
Let's look into the members of Kessoku Band!
The unexpected past of super-popular guitarist
Hitori Gotoh, whose cool personality, skillful playing,
and raw lyrics have captured the hearts of fans!
Hitori Gotoh
Q. Did you know your high school classmate
Hitori Gotoh has become a famous guitarist?
Hitori Gotoh had become a famous guitarist?
Did you know your high school classmate
Wow, Gotoh-san was in a band back then?
I should've gotten her autograph!
I'll just follow that model instead!
I like it.
Now that I've got a plan in mind,
I don't feel so bad about it.
Good work, me!
Gotoh-san!
Morning!
G-Good morning...
How are you feeling?
I got worried and stopped
by the nurse's office again yesterday,
but you were already gone.
R-Really? I'm sorry...
Oh, and I turned it in.
For the culture festival performance!
We'll be on stage as Kessoku Band!
I just can't wait!
The application must've fallen
in the trash can by mistake.
What a close call, right?
Let's put on the best
culture festival concert ever!
So that's why she's been like that.
I was so sure she wanted to do it.
She seemed very excited yesterday.
Wh-What do I do?
I am a criminal.
Right?
They're going to label me a murderer!
It's not too late to back out, is it?
They said you can't take it back
once you've applied...
But I'll talk to them tomorrow.
Hey-ho! Free booze, please!
Hell no. Piss off.
Aw, c'mon!
Tell yer sister to be nicer!
You like havin' me around, right, li'l sis?
Kindly depart. We're about
to open for business.
You've got a death glare
on par with Senpai's lately.
Bocchi-chan!
What's with her? Somethin' on her mind?
I volunteered us for the culture
festival against her will.
What? You gonna play there?
I c-can't do it.
Th-There'd be so many more
people than I'm used to,
a-and I'm s-scared of performing in
front of people who know me at s-school.
Bocchi-chan.
For you!
Payin' you back for before.
My band's playin' a gig tonight!
Wanna come see?
C-Can I?
'Course you can!
Same goes for all y'all.
Thank you very much.
Let me pay you.
Yes, for the tickets.
Aw, don't go there. It's a gift!
But...
Please, let us pay!
H-Hang on, do you think
I'm some kind of broke rocker
who's gotta hustle money from teenage girls?
You mean you're not?
Damn it! Senpai, one bottle of shochu!
Like hell, dumbass.
Anyhoo, it's fine!
I might not look it, but our band's
pretty popular on the indies circuit!
Right?
Yes, they have many hardcore fans.
Which means we make our ticket quotas, easy!
We even make money on merch!
Then why do you only drink the cheap stuff?
And you use our shower, too.
Pay rent.
You never paid me back for your train fare.
Sounds like a hustle to me!
Th-There's a reason for all this...
All my money goes to paying for the
equipment I break while playing drunk.
So it's your own fault.
Bocchi-chan, has she borrowed any more
money from you that she hasn't paid back?
N-No... she hasn't...
Garbage humans.
Apologize for your late repayment.
Sorry for our lateness!
I-It's okay...
Noguchi-sensei... farewell...
You really need to cut back.
You never used to drink before
you started playing concerts.
It can't be good for you.
C'mon, that's no biggie!
Now, let's all go to Shinjuku!
I can't hear you!
Do you think she can really play like that?
You're supposed to say "go!"
Getting to see SICK HACK for free...
My soul is on fire!
SICK HACK? Is that the name
of Hiroi-san's band?
Yep!
I knew she was good
from our street concert...
But I don't really know
what she sounds like.
I'm kind of looking forward to this!
I v-very much enjoyed the concert...
Thank you for having me...
We're not even at the venue yet!
Here's my home base, Shinjuku FOLT!
C'mon in, y'all!
The vibe is very different from Starry's...
Hey, no worries. It's the same kind of place.
It is a little scary,
but I feel strangely confident.
Clubs are the same wherever you—
Th-Thank you for the wonderful concert!
Seriously, it hasn't started yet!
I w-was a fool to think
I'd grown as a person...
I'm sure they're nice people
if you talk to them!
Gin-chan! Mornin'!
Yeah?
I m-miss my sister!
It's gotten to Ijichi-senpai too!
This is the manager, Gin-chan!
H-Hello!
Oh, gosh, look at all the cute
little buddies you brought!
I'm Ginjiro Yoshida, 37 years old!
Punk rock's my genre of choice!
The contrast between how he looks and talks
kinda shorts out your brain, right?
But don't worry.
Gin-chan's a nice old guy
with the heart of a pure maiden!
Hey, Hiroi.
Yeah?
For the millionth time, don't be late.
Our rehearsal's already over!
Sorry!
But it'll all work out, I bet!
Are these the members of Kessoku Band?
Y-Yes!
And you're...
She's part of SICK HACK.
I'm Shima, the drummer.
A pleasure.
It's such a pleasure to meet you!
I'm sure our Hiroi's caused
a lot of trouble for you.
If this will in any way make up for it...
Sh-She's so polite!
Oh, th-thank you!
Maybe the other band members balance her out?
I'm Eliza! I lived in England
until I was eighteen.
This is my third year in Japan.
Let's be friends!
You came all the way to
Japan to be in a band?
Do you like J-Rock?
No. Actually, I came to Japan for Comiket!
I really wanna be in an anisong cover band!
Eliza's always saying anisongs are
Japan's real bleeding-edge sound!
The three of them are...
Balanced?
I bought this in Asakusa!
Nice one!
Stop now.
Here you are.
Thank you!
Look at all the people!
There's at least two hundred here.
I had no idea her band was this popular...
By the way, where's Ryo?
She was with us just minutes ago...
Eh?
She's sitting over there!
Sh-She's doing...
the club classic: the "I'm not like you
overexcited sheeple" customer!
Take in the sound. The sound!
Ryo-senpai.
What kind of band is SICK HACK, exactly?
They play psychedelic rock.
A genre that spread in the 1960s as a musical
expression of drug-induced hallucinations
whose influence led to many progressive
rock bands getting their start...
I've never seen Senpai talk
so much about anything.
I c-can't wait to hear them.
Yeah!
I'm kinda interested in psychedelic rock!
Really?
I'll bring all my albums tomorrow.
It's best for a beginner
to start from the second.
Better watch what you say, Kita-chan.
That kind of line will get
you mobbed by fanatics.
Up late doing spot-the-difference puzzles
Oh, what fun
A lost child beckons me to a land of dreams
Their band's amazing.
The drum's spot-on irregular time
signature that keeps you off-balance.
This-a-way, that-a-way
The emotional yet overwhelmingly
logical playing of the guitar...
Which way is the way?
My life's run out of battery
And the bass forms a wall of sound
that supports it all.
But now it's time, let's party
But the most amazing thing of all...
I can't tell you how much
I admire your philanthropy
is her overwhelming charisma!
All of you, all of you...
For the time they're standing on stage,
Round and round and round, let's dance
performers are heroes!
Hot and sweaty and close, you swirl around me
A band really is
I've got toast spread thick with lies
the coolest thing ever!
Would you like to try?
There's only one ghost, and it's me
Bocchi-chan! How'd you like my show?
I-It was great.
That was so good!
Hey, what's got you so down?
Thanks!
We stunk the place up after all?
N-Not at all.
You really were incredible.
But I... er...
You were really shining up there.
I don't think I could... ever...
Lemme fill you in here.
Up to high school, I was the gloomy misfit
sittin' in a corner of the classroom.
Could ya tell?
I guess it's true what they say:
gloomy people attract.
But sometimes I'd imagine what
my future was gonna look like,
and I'd think, "C'mon, that's lame!"
I started playing rock
to make my life's course do a 180.
At first, I was scared stiff of buying a bass
at the music shop or going into a club.
The whole reason I started drinking was
to chill myself out before our first concert.
Everyone's scared when they
do something for the first time.
But you played just fine,
both on the street and at Starry!
And you didn't even need alcohol to do it!
You mean...
Have a little faith in yourself!
And if that's not enough,
have a drink to take the edge off!
I-I'm really too young.
But I'd like you to come to our
culture festival performance.
Yeah, that's the way!
I'm adding 100,000 to your tab
for wall repairs.
Th-That one's partly Bocchi-chan's fault!
Okay!
Now that the concert's got us all hyped up,
let's plot our culture festival setlist!
Kita-chan said each band
gets fifteen minutes.
So that's about three songs, right?
H-Hey...
C-Can't I let Ryo-senpai have some of mine?
No!
She needs to learn her lesson
for bumming off of Bocchi-chan for so long.
Ikuyo...
Kita-chan! Don't fall for our
wicked bandmate's tricks!
The three Bs to avoid in a boyfriend are
"bassist, bassist, and bassist," after all!
I'll never borrow money from anyone again.
Then I gift you this.
You're kind, Nijika. I love you.
The legit gratitude is tugging
on my heartstrings, darn it!
Just help yourself already!
I already know our setlist.
I've been thinking it over since
the culture festival came up.
Nice!
We'll put a Bocchi guitar solo
in the second one.
To make sure you shine.
It's your and Ikuyo's
culture festival, remember?
But isn't going all-original in the
culture festival a bit aggressive?
So what? Let's be aggressive!
And if we bomb, there's four of us.
We can split the shame four ways.
Ryo, are you trying to push
your trauma on the rest of us?
Guitar solo...
K-Kita-san?
G-Gotoh-san...
I...
I knew you'd thrown out the
culture festival application!
But I submitted it anyway.
I'm so, so sorry that I lied!
Th-Thank you for doing it.
I w-was pretty freaked out at first,
but now I'm kind of looking forward to it.
Th-That wouldn't have happened
if you hadn't turned in the application.
So I'm really grateful.
Thank you.
Gotoh-san, I'm going to work
even harder at practice than ever!
So let's make our culture
festival concert a success!
O-Okay.
The truth is, I really wanted Gotoh-san
to perform at the culture festival.
Because Gotoh-san is...
Ryo-senpai!
Would you be willing to coach me
on guitar after work?
Isn't Bocchi coaching you?
Gotoh-san has her own practice to focus on.
I want to practice and get better too!
You heard her.
Humor her, okay?
My lessons don't come cheap.
Okay!
How come Bocchi-chan's not with you today?
Well... she's got make-up lessons...
31st Annual Shuka Festival
Bocchi-chan's missing?!
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#11 Duodecimal Sunset
Watch it.