I hate it when I'm right.
Nijika and her friends made them.
But the typhoon still came in the end.
Well, it's not like rain charms
actually affect the weather.
Even the people who bought tickets
might not come at this rate.
I hope they're not too
heartbroken by the small crowd.
They practiced so hard for this.
I feel bad for them.
Real bands get screwed over
by life all the time.
They need to learn to make it
through any situation.
I've got a handkerchief.
Oh, go away.
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Looks like my friends can't come either.
S-Same with my parents.
M-My grandma was supposed
to look after Futari,
b-but now she can't come, so...
Yeah. Makes sense...
Our audience is going to be
less than half of what we expected.
Well, it is what it is!
Let's take it in stride!
Yes, of course!
Nijika-chan always stays so cheerful,
no matter what happens.
C'mon, look alive there!
It's the low-pressure system. So sleepy...
That's right. Even during the concert
where I was just helping...
She worked so hard to cheer me up
when I was scared.
O-Okay!
For today's concert...
Sergeant for a Day
I'm gonna bring the hype!
Bocchi-chan, this is a serious concert.
No messing around.
You really like that outfit, huh?
Y-Yes...
Wow, look at that rain!
Bocchi-chan, I'm here!
M-Ma'am!
Oh, you came here for Bocchi-chan?
Heck yeah! Yay!
Y-You know each other?
She was my junior in college.
Betcher havin' an afterparty tonight, right?
Picked an izakaya yet?
You reek of booze!
I know a good one, 'kay? 'Kay?
How did you become even more
of a pain in the ass?
She's as annoying as a college student
who just learned about drinking parties.
And look at you! You're soaked!
I'm so wet!
Hitori-chan!
The girls from our street concert!
Y-You really came?
Of course we did!
We're your fans!
We'll be expecting a performance
powerful enough to blow away the typhoon!
Fans...
Y-You are Hitori-chan, right?
Did we have the wrong person?
My fans!
Congrats! Congrats! Congrats!
It is the wrong person!
Looks like the rain's
only going to get worse.
Worse than this?
Yes...
Maybe we should just stream it
as a no-audience concert
and act like it was supposed
to be that way from the start.
We're not doing that!
It's way too late to get anyone to tune in,
and we've already got a couple people here...
I-I-I-It'll be okay!
A-As long as we have p-people
waiting to see us p-perform!
Ripe Mangos
Don't you dare!
She's evolved somehow...
Ripe Mangos
It's just about start time, and there's
really not many people out there...
But the other bands' fans are here too,
and I'm sure they'll all listen to us!
And I'm sure more will arrive if we start.
Hey, you ever heard of this
first group? Kessoku Band?
Don't know. Don't care.
Yeah, seems like a waste of time.
W-Well, we're new,
so of course no one knows us!
Don't let it get you down!
E-Exactly!
Don't sweat it. Don't sweat it.
R-Right!
O-Okay, it's almost time!
Let's do that concert, you guys!
A pleasure to meet you!
We're Kessoku Band!
We appreciate your kind attendance
in spite of this awful weather!
Kita-chan, that's way too polite
for a rock band!
I want my mango box!
Actually, I want to disappear altogether!
Well, let's get to that first song!
Please lend your ears to our original song:
"Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet"!
A sudden evening shower falls
And yeah, it figures,
I don't have an umbrella...
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
When it's time for the seasons to change
What are you supposed to wear? Who knows?
Nijika-chan's drumming feels a little slow.
Spring and fall... yeah, where'd they go?
The pressure of information, suffocating
And Kita-san's making mistakes
she didn't make in practice.
A spiral of vertigo
Ryo-san and Nijika-chan
aren't in sync at all.
Don't know where I am
I can hear myself breathing
so loud, so loud...
But why? I can't hear the
sounds of the world...
It's not enough, not enough,
No one knows I'm here
I screamed when I couldn't
make a scribble of a sound
We're not playing the way we usually do...
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
So I'm singing just like the fool I am
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
That was "Guitar, Solitude,
and the Blue Planet"!
Yeah, what a waste of time.
We should've showed up later.
Um...
Kita-chan, you need to
introduce the next song!
R-Right!
The next is another of our original songs,
and it's one we just wrote...
Our performance and
our songs still aren't good enough.
But...
I refuse to let it stay this way!
That band's songs sound to me
like shrill laughter all around
That band's songs are to me
like the piercing clang of a railway crossing
Don't push me forward
There's a train coming
I close my eyes
There's a halo in the darkness
I cover my ears
There's a steady beating pulse within
Deep in my chest
My heart makes my body sway
I don't want to hear anything else
Nothing but the sounds I'm making
Hey, not bad!
Yeah!
That was super cool!
Magnificent smugface.
That was our second song, "That Band"!
Now, here's our last song!
Kaomise
Cheers!
Well done, all!
Nice work on the concert.
This is all on my tab, so drink up.
Thanks, Sis! Though we don't drink...
Love ya, Senpai!
You pay your own way. Get off.
Who exactly is this woman, if I may ask?
Genius bassist and unparalleled
bass-lover, Kikuri Hiroi!
I left my bass at a drinking party yesterday,
but I forgot which drinking party, so...
Instant self-contradiction.
I've been to a lot of your concerts.
Aw, for real? You got good taste, hon!
You spray booze on the audience.
Blind drunk concerts are the best!
Sorry, forgot the words!
But hey, that's how concerts go sometimes!
Don't be mad, you jerks!
I treasure my memory of
you stepping on my face.
Thank you, Shinjuku!
I love you mother******s!
There's so much about rock
I have yet to learn.
It might be okay not to learn all that.
Glad your concert turned out well in the end!
For an audience of ten, sure.
But every single one of 'em left happy!
Yeah, guess so!
Well, keep it up, and you'll pick up fans.
Work hard for your next concert.
And make sure you pay your quota fee.
That'd be really inspiring
without the last bit...
You worked really hard today too,
Bocchi-chan...
Wait, why's she a husk?!
Bocchi-chan, don't turn to ash!
I've grown so tired...
Congrats! Congrats!
That's the wrong show!
Go on, order as much food as you like!
R-Right...
Watcha gettin', Bocchi-chan?
I was thinking of ordering karaage!
S-Sounds good...
What are you doing?
But this looks pretty good too!
Isstagramming!
I'm the minister!
Minister?
What do you like so much about that, anyway?
What?
I guess it's like
giving people a piece of the fun...
Isn't everything more fun when
you share it with your friends?
Kit-aura
Kit-aura!
Nice!
Use that Kita-chan power of yours
to purge my sister's twisted spirit!
Twisted?
But the manager's really nice!
Kit-aura
Kit-aura! Kit-aura!
Stop it.
You're killing me.
I-I've made up my mind. Here's the menu.
Thanks!
Let's see...
I'll have the avocado and
cream cheese pinchos!
And the Spanish omelette
with hollandaise sauce!
The what?
Here! The omelette with hollandaise.
Hollanda-what?
Kita-san's so fluent in trendy gibberish.
Nice! Nice!
Keep ordering!
I bet she can casually
walk into a Starpucks.
I bet she could make the most complicated
orders like it was nothing.
I'll have a short puri-puri pepero
papipupepo peroppe pacina!
Kit-aura!
Bocchi-chan? What do you want?
Oh...
I w-won't be the way I usually am!
I'll make a trendy choice too!
Bocchi-chan?
Th-Then, I'll have the M-Machu Picchu Ruins,
Mississippi River,
Grand Canyon San Diego hash...
M-Machu Picchu, Machu Picchu, Machu Picchu...
Where's that exactly?
Oh, I read it wrong...
I meant fries.
How did you read that wrong?
Pickled fish offals for me.
How old're you again?
You're already moving on?
Izakayas are like my home ground, y'know?
Hey, how do you read this one?
It's my first time at an izakaya,
Which one? I don't think
I can read it either...
but they're actually kind of fun...
You're so knowledgeable, Ryo-senpai!
I wonder if they'll be even more fun
when I grow up and can drink.
My wife's taste in clothing
changed all of a sudden.
And she suddenly started
locking her smartphone.
What, you check your wife's phone?
No, I just happened to notice.
Sounds like cheating to me.
Yeah, gotta be...
But maybe I deserve it.
I'm so busy with work every day...
You don't deserve it.
Hours of unpaid overtime, forced to spend
my days off golfing with clients...
And when I do get an early break,
I have such a hard time facing her
I go drinking with you instead...
What am I even doing all this work for?
Hey, you all right, man?
Sometimes I look at the station platform, and
I find myself about to jump onto the tracks.
C'mon, have some more to drink.
Excuse me! More shochu!
Sure thing! One shochu!
Is life just an unrelenting hell?
If I can't make my stage
debut in high school,
I'm going to have to get a proper career too.
I'm not smart enough to get into college,
Fail to make debut,
get a job
Graduate high school
Move on to college
and I don't even know what I'd go for...
Sales Results for December
Target: 100
Gotoh            Ozaki            Hasegawa         Koizumi           Ogawa
5th              4th                  3rd                2nd                 1st
Your sales for this month were the
lowest on the team, Gotoh-san.
Gotoh-san again?
It's partly the boss being cruel.
He transferred her to sales
to try to make her quit!
Tokoroten
E-Excuse me...
W-Would you like to buy some tokoroten?
It's well-aged, and it goes down smooth...
No, thank you!
Transferred to
sales department
Fail at door-
to-door sales
Stress quit and
become a shut-in
I see as plain as day
where my Game of Life is going!
Hitori-chan, won't you open up? Please?
You don't have to go back to work.
Just come eat dinner with me again!
Please?
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
Another of Bocchi-chan's episodes?
Oh, so that is typical for her!
If I can't make money with my guitar,
I'll end up a NEET.
Her face is scary when it gets like that.
If I can't make money with my guitar...
Really? I think it's got personality.
Are you for real?
Sandpaper, please.
It's kind of a chore, huh?
Whoops. Think I botched it.
It's okay.
Just do it like this. See?
They're used to it!
Up we go.
Did I make her face too long?
I think it's about right.
Oh, thank you!
A-Actually, can I fix it up a little?
By the way, Ikuyo.
You played pretty well today for only
having done this for three months.
Huh? Who's Ikuyo again?
Dunno! Who'd have a crummy
old name like that?!
It's your name, isn't it?!
Oh, it's Kita-chan's name?
That face is contagious, huh?
I hid it for so long!
I hate my name so much!
How come? It's cute.
You wouldn't understand,
since you have a beautiful name
that means "song of the stars"!
Look at her freak out!
But mine sounds like a bad pun!
"Kita! Ikuyo!" (I'm here! Let's go!)
Are you serious?!
I think we broke her.
My full name is Kita Kita.
Seeing you withdraw into your shell is fun.
You're sadistic.
So, as for what you were saying before...
You were mumbling about supporting yourself
with the guitar and becoming a NEET.
I-I'm sorry for losing my head...
Hey, nothin' wrong with it.
But lemme give you some advice
as your senpai in the world of bands.
Just chill out and enjoy yourself!
If you put the weight of success
on your own shoulders all the time,
you'll just make yourself miserable.
That's right.
It's important to enjoy the process
of making your dream come true.
By the way, Senpai, how come
you suddenly quit playing?
Th-The manager was in a band?
Oh, yah. They were super popular.
Then wh-why...
I got sick of bands.
But you run a club.
What's the deal there, huh?
Shut up and drink.
Nijika-chan never said a word about that...
What, I can? Thanks a bunch!
Huh? And Nijika-chan's been gone a while...
I'm not paying for you, though.
Aww...
E-Excuse me.
I have to use the restroom.
Manager, keep 'em comin'!
E-Excuse me... Nijika-chan?
Oh, Bocchi-chan!
I-Is something the matter?
Nah, just getting some fresh air.
I-It's been getting cold
at night lately, huh?
Sure has.
Next thing we know,
summer break's gonna be over!
I hear nothing.
I know nothing.
Summer break never ends.
I'm not a student.
Trees, water, planets, Milky Way...
Bocchi-chan! Back to reality!
S-Sorry.
E-Excuse me...
Say...
I realized something while I was
watching you play today.
You're guitarhero, aren't you?
W-Well, a-actually, n-no, about that...
It was pretty obvious from the
on-point way you were strumming.
And I finally noticed
you had the same guitar.
No use trying to hide it now.
Um...
I am.
B-But I didn't hide it on purpose.
S-Since I'm anything but a hero right now...
I w-wanted to wait to tell you
until I fixed the way I am.
E-Especially you, Nijika-chan.
A-Are you shocked to find out?
Nah...
It made me all the more happy to have you!
What?
See, I told you I had a dream before, right?
Y-Yes?
My mom died when I was little,
and my dad was never home,
so my sister was pretty much my only family.
But since I hated being alone,
when my sis started a band,
I had her take me to her clubs all the time.
It all seemed so shining to me.
I was never happier anywhere else.
I was her inspiration for quitting her band
and starting up this club.
Starry is a place my sister made for me.
Though I'll bet she won't admit it.
So my real dream
is to make a band popular
enough for me and my sister
and make Starry even more famous!
But when I actually started my band,
I spent a while thinking that
it was kind of out of my reach.
And everyone was so disheartened today.
But every time things
are looking their worst,
Ripe Mangos
you're the one who breaks through it for us!
Bocchi-chan, you were
one heck of a hero to me today.
Ryo wants to use this band to finally
get to play music from the heart,
and Kita-chan wants to really
do something with us.
They've all invested their hopes in the band.
That reminds me, you never actually told me
what you were doing the band for now.
I...
As a guitarist, I want to make the
Kessoku Band we all care so much about
the best band it can be!
A-And I want us to become such a popular band
that we can make money
and not have to finish school...
That's a pretty tall order!
But I accept your investment!
I sure do wish you could play the way
you do in your videos every time, though...
I'll d-do my best...
But now I know it for sure!
Having you with us will
make our dreams possible!
So keep showing us more and more.
Of "Bocchi-chan's rock."
Bocchi the Rock!
Okay!
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#08 Bocchi the Rock
What's wrong with being young?
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#08 Bocchi the Rock
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#09 Enoshima Escar
Watch it!