31st Annual
Shuka Festival Day 1
Anyone want a hot dog?
Churros!!
Shuka High School
Cotton Candy
Class 2-2's doing a haunted house!
2-2
Haunted
Hospital
Boy, even the first day is a total event!
Not at all like our school!
Hey, where do you wanna start?
Dunno...
I'd love to try Class 2's haunted house!
Spin!
Pumpkin
Somen
Enthusiasts
Awesome! Let's do it!
Sumo Club Ring Experience
It's like an entire school of Ikuyos.
Well, anyway...
I think Bocchi-chan's class is nearby,
so let's check that out!
Hey, bet this's it!
Hi-ho! Is Bocchi-chan in?
Serve us, Bocchi.
Senpai...
Cafe
Kita-chan! Did you come to see
Bocchi-chan in her maid costume too?
Where's the Bocchi-chan maid?
About that...
What?!
Bocchi-chan vanished?!
Maid Cafe
She put on her maid costume and
said she was going to the bathroom.
We haven't seen her since.
I wish she could've just told us
if she didn't want to do it.
You'd think running around the school
as a maid would be even more embarrassing...
But whatever. Let's get searching!
Right!
No whining, you!
Area ahead
off limits
No Bocchi-chan here...
Where could she have gone?
Maybe we should check
all the women's bathrooms?
All of them?
No...
Darwin Kita!
Breaking! Learning about the top-secret
ecosystem of the Hitori Gotoh
Gotoh-san won't be found in such
a constantly inhabited location!
Aha!
Where should we look, then?
Teach us, Professor Kita!
Allow me to elucidate!
It must be uninhabited!
It must be damp and depressing.
We must search the kinds of ecosystems
in which one might find slugs.
She might be found beneath a rock, perchance!
Effortlessly brutal.
I lied and ran off without thinking about it.
I'm gonna make trouble for
everyone if I don't get back.
But I'll die from embarrassment
if my band sees me like this.
If only I had my ripe mangos...
Ripe Mangos
Welcome home!
I long for the warmth
of that cardboard box...
It's no use.
I'm gonna drive myself crazy like this.
I need escapism.
Let's retreat to the online world.
I've been so busy with rehearsals,
I haven't looked in ages...
Kaopin  3 Days Ago
Thanks for the upload!!
I already can't wait for the next vid
mou rock  5 Days Ago
Are you self-taught? It's amazing you got
this good like that. You must've worked
really hard!
Nekomi  1 Week Ago
Been watching from the start!!!
As usual, I'm so jealous of your talent!
BGB  1 Week Ago
Wow!! New content at last!!!!
One of my fave songs, too! Thanks so much!
Gomachin  1 Week Ago
How'd your view count get so crazy so quick?!
guitarhero's been found by the world at last!
Papa Mikan  2 Weeks Ago
I watch a lot of cover videos,
and you're the best of them all!
My comments section is the
nicest place in the world.
Every single comment is kind and—
Did she drop her channel?
I might have to unsubscribe...
guitarhero's de*d, I guess.
C-C-Crud!
I-If I don't upload a video, my home...
I'll lose my online home!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#11 Duodecimal Sunset
H-Huh?
When was the last time I uploaded again?
I've been so busy, I haven't even
had time to think about it...
I'll put something up
the minute the culture festival's over!
Hey, there she is!
Bocchi-chan, your whole class
is worried about you!
In a place you'd find slugs...
You called it.
I feel justified in rummaging
through those trash cans and cisterns!
Though it sorta stopped feeling like
we were looking for a person...
Anyway, come on back, would you?
'Kay...
Hey, look!
October 2nd
10:00~ Chorus Club Opening
Band Club/Volunteer Performances!!
12:00~ Hakumai Bakery
12:30~ Alumi-can Mikan
13:00~ Chaos eden
13:30~ Kessoku Band
14:00~ Miracle Love Romance
Right here!
Kessoku Band
It's got our name on it!
But of course it does, right?
Seeing Kessoku Band's name in our school
does feel odd, doesn't it?
Y-Yeah.
Don't get too worked up now.
You'll just exhaust yourself.
R-Right!
Let's take the day to just
enjoy the culture festival!
Right, Gotoh-san?
Unlike Kita-chan, I've never actually
enjoyed a school event...
2-2
Haunted
Hospital
Line for the Class 2-2
haunted house ends here!
Haunted Hospital
One person incoming!
I've been really curious about this!
You think we can take a little detour?
I'd like to try it too!
It's getting great reviews!
Handmade Crêpes
Can we take another detour?
One chocolate crêpe!
Chocolate banana?
Thank you!
Or should I go with something more tart?
Buy both, and give me some.
You bet!
Hey, no casual extortion.
Yogurt
Eh?
Is that Bocchi-chan?!
It's almost like...
Here we go...
Gotcha!
Economy Size
Congratulations!
String Lottery
Yeah!
Nice work, Senpai!
Doing the culture festival
as a group is actually pretty fun.
Easy-peasy!
Thanks for winning that for me.
It's not for you.
And...
Wh-Where to next?
Good enthusiasm!
Let's keep going until
we do the full circuit!
I think you're having too much fun!
And Gotoh-san has this...
The longer
we mess
around out here,
"The longer we mess around out here,
the later I get back to the maid cafe!"
the later I get
back to
the maid cafe!
...look on her face!
B-Busted!
Maid Cafe
Welcome to Class 1-2's maid cafe!
Welcome home!
Sit right here!
Gotoh-san's class really went all-out!
They all look so cute!
And Gotoh-san's doing a great job standing
up straight and looking customers in the eye!
I guess working for us
really helped her out, huh?
No!
She's just passed out on her feet.
Maid Cafe
You're right!
Not good.
A gang of post-apocalyptic hooligans...
Who let them into the school?!
Hey, babe.
Maid Cafe
How's about you drop the sign
and have a little fun with us?!
Dead
My charge didn't even faze her!
She's even got the confidence
to make faces at us!
Demon
She's somethin' else!
Forgive us for our arrogance!
Gotoh-san's amazing!
She's being so helpful!
Y-Yeah... I guess.
Bocchi-chan, we're ready to order!
Wh-Wh-What can I get you?!
Let's see...
Hey...
Anyone else notice how good Bocchi-chan
looks in that maid outfit?
You look so good in frilly stuff, Gotoh-san!
Yeah, totes!
I wish you wouldn't wear that
tracksuit all the time.
W-Well, I...
1-2 Maid Cafe
Wh-What is it?
Some bands do push the visual aspect...
I never knew you were such an uncut gem!
R-Ryo-san?
We'll have you in a swimsuit in the video.
I Tried Playing in a Swimsuit!
For modern bands,
it's views that do the talking!
And bringing in those views requires
a few sacrifices here and there!
Reel
[Kessoku Band] I Tried Playing in a Swimsuit!
Original Song
No, no, no, no, no, no!
We'll wrap you in black tape
and have you play on the ocean!
Stop using Bocchi-chan as a cash cow!
P-Please just order!
Oh, right...
Can someone spot me?
Sure-Pure Melt-
in-Your-Mouth
Magic Omurice
Unicorn Fantasy Dream
Sparkle-Shine Omurice
Lie-4-U Die-4-U
Sickly-Chic Omurice
Bouncy Boingy Hype-it-Up
Festival Mood Omurice
Mega-Squee Zing-a-Ling
Lose-My-Mind Omurice
And water on the house!
Wow, it looks delicious!
How about this?
What's the Sure-Pure
Melt-in-Your-Mouth Magic Omurice?
It's just normal omurice.
And the Unicorn Fantasy
Dream Sparkle-Shine Omurice?
That's also normal omurice.
And the Lie-4-U Die-4-U Sickly-Chic Omurice?
It's... normal omurice.
So it's all the same thing
with different names?!
We spent all our budget on the costumes.
O-One Sure-Pure M-Melt-in-Your-Mouth
Magic Omurice...
Excuse me!
Deliciousness spell:
No charge
And water on the house!
I'd like one of these deliciousness spells,
if you please!
Oh, w-well...
The customer's always right.
Smirk
Smirk, smirk. Smirk, smirk.
Help us out, Miss Maid!
You guys are really enjoying this...
Sure-sure pure-pure miracle squee omurice...
Become delicious.
Kind of grainy.
Yeah, we bought them frozen...
Gotoh-san! You need to put
more love into the spell!
Watch me work!
Just like this!
Sure-sure!
Pure-pure!
Miracle...
Squee!
If you please, omurice...
Become delicious!
Kit-aura
The acidity of the ketchup
and sweetness of the sauce blend together,
giving it the soul-warming feel
of home cooking!
Smooth!
Kita-chan!
Would you mind helping our class out?
Could I?!
I'd love to wear the costume!
How do I look?
Kita-chan, you look so good!
You're wearing the heck out of that thing!
Would you guys like to wear one, too?
For the memory!
What? Can we?
Of course you can!
Crazy cute!
Hold it!
Let's have Senpai in "big sister" style!
Or... What about boy style?!
A fabulous choice, if I do say so myself!
Isn't she getting a bit too excited
compared to with me?
But the three of you together
make such a powerful visual!
Would you be willing to help us out a while?
No prob!
I already work in customer service,
so I got this handled!
Thank you!
Welcome home!
What bands are you here to see today?
Ijichi-senpai, this is a maid cafe!
Incredible.
Kita-san and Nijika-chan have
such overwhelming adaptability
Ah, I slipped into my usual work persona!
and customer service powers!
'Scuse me!
Could I have s'more water?
Ryo-senpai, you take care of them!
Heh.
You want it? Come get it.
F-F-Forgive us for our arrogance!
This isn't the club!
Still hot, though!
R-Ryo has her own inexplicable power, too...
Thanks!
Y-Y-Yeah!
Hey!
I brought a group!
Uh-oh!
Welcome home!
Come right this way!
Gotoh-san, you can take a break!
S-Sure...
This difference in reception...
It feels like a preview
of tomorrow's concert!
Butler Café Tomorrow
Please stop by!
Awesome!
We're sold out of omurice already!
I bet we take first place
in the class sales rankings!
We owe it to Kita-chan
and the rest of your band!
Thank you so much!
Hey, it's no biggie! We had fun too!
Thanks!
We'll totally come to watch
your concert tomorrow!
Awesome! Please do!
And what about our fee?
Don't tell me you expected us
to work for free...
C'mon!
We gotta go practice!
Waaaagh...
But first, could we do one thing?
I wanted to get a look
at our venue before we left!
Wow, what a pretty gym!
The max occupancy must be around a thousand.
I doubt we'll get that
many people, of course...
But I sure hope we get a lot!
Y-Yeah...
You bet we will!
We've got Kita-chan power on our side!
R-Right...
31st Annual Shuka Festival
I'll be standing up there tomorrow...
Together with Kessoku Band!
I've been thinking, Bocchi-chan...
Your guitar's pretty old, isn't it?
I noticed that too!
The frets are rusty,
plus the hairline cracks...
It's a well-used vintage item, right?
It could sell for quite a lot—
Stop putting a price on everything.
Um, I'm borrowing the one my dad used
when he was younger...
So I guess it is pretty old.
He's coming with your family tomorrow, right?
Y-Yeah...
He couldn't make it to our concert
because of the storm,
but he was pretty excited.
He even bought a camcorder!
Vibes in the house!
I can totally imagine it!
My friends sent me a LOINE message about
how much they're looking forward to it!
All the more reason to give it our best!
Y-Yeah, guess so!
Oh, right...
What kind of MCing should
I do for tomorrow's concert?
Introduce us, the songs,
and add a little commentary, I guess?
Th-That sounds good to me.
Well, what we do now is fine...
But I thought a little funny MCing
like popular bands do might be fun.
Band MCing is never funny.
Fans just laugh along to humor them.
Opinions expressed are solely Yamada's
Way too harsh!
Once we get popular, even your lousiest
MCing will pick up big laughs.
Don't worry.
Is that a reassurance or a diss?!
Break-up imminent!
Now, now!
No fighting!
Let's finish our practice!
Right, sorry. Let's do it!
Okay, here we go!
Sounds great!
Huh?
Yeah.
That was wonderful!
Kita-san's kind of...
What's the matter, Gotoh-san?
Oh, I thought...
I just really hope people enjoy our concert!
Yeah, I know they will!
That's good. Be confident.
We're counting on you, Bocchi-chan!
We all need to have self-confidence.
I think you'll knock everyone's socks off!
Oh, I doubt that...
You totally will!
Because you're so amazingly...
No... Never mind.
Let's just do our best!
R-Right!
Well, that's all for today!
In preparation for tomorrow,
let's all get to bed early!
Right!
Good work today, all!
It's got that autumn feeling, huh?
I figured we'd be working on
our first mini-album by now.
We're making steady progress.
That's all that matters!
It's almost here.
Kessoku Band
The festival performance.
October 2nd
10:00~ Chorus Club Opening
Band Club/Volunteer Performances!!
12:00~ Hakumai Bakery
12:30~ Alumi-can Mikan
13:00~ Chaos eden
13:30~ Kessoku Band
14:00~ Miracle Love Romance
14:30~ Churu-Churu
15:00~ Guidance Department
(Staff Band)
See you then!
My first performance in front of the school.
31st Shuka Festival
I can't be as confident as Kita-san is.
But I do hope they enjoy us!
31st Annual
Shuka Festival
Day 2
My sister said she'd be here too!
Wow, really?
Okay, girl. Have faith in yourself!
Trust that it's all going to go right.
What if...
What if a record company
producer is in the audience?
Magnifique! You deserve a debut contract!
High School Band
Kessoku Band
The success story of a high school band...
High School Band
Kessoku Band
Maybe it'll make the news,
and we'll become a legend!
Back in her own little world, huh?
31st Annual Shuka Festival
Gym Stage Time Schedule
October 1st
10:00~  Concert Band: Opening
12:00~
Drama Club: New Romeo and Juliet
14:00~
Manzai Enthusiasts (Shu-ka)
S-1 Grand Prix
16:00~
Volunteer, "Miseinen no Maruhari"
~Until the teachers get mad at us~
17:00~  Planned End
October 2nd
10:00~ Chorus Club Opening
Band Club/Volunteer Performances!!
12:00~ Hakumai Bakery
12:30~ Alumi-can Mikan
13:00~ Chaos eden
13:30~ Kessoku Band
14:00~ Miracle Love Romance
14:30~ Churu-Churu
15:00~ Guidance Department
(Staff Band)
See you then!
Time to go, Bocchi-chan!
C-Coming!
They're loving the band before us, huh?
They're playing a big
hit song from this year.
Who waves glowsticks at a rock concert?
I'm so nervous now!
Kita-chan! Deep breaths!
Bocchi-chan! You okay?
Yes!
Six months ago she had to wear the mango box,
and now she's facing it head-on!
Thump
Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump  Thump                      Thump                      Thump                      Thump                      Thump                      Thump                      Thump                      Thump
Why's this band's drummer so loud?
Gotoh-san, you breathe too!
Deep breath in... Deep breath out.
Kessoku Band! You're up soon!
Right!
Okay! Wanna do a huddle?
Oh! Or that thing where we put
our hands together and go "Yeah!"
I love it! Let's do it!
So stuffy.
Left hands, all!
Okay!
Just do it already!
You too, Gotoh-san!
R-Right.
Now, let's play hard and have fun!
One, two...
Yeah!
Our next band is Kessoku Band!
Kita-chan!
31st Annual Shuka Festival
Hi!
It's just what I expected.
Big Sis!
Give it your best!
Hitori-chan!
M-My fans!
Give it your best!
People from my class, too...
It's not just what I expected!
Hey!
Kick ass up there, Bocchi-chan!
Hey, look!
'Cuz today's special, I'm drinkin'
the kind that comes in glasses!
Onikoro Sake
Gimme a good show, 'kay?!
Reeks of booze!
I'm not sure she should be here...
Huh? Whu?
Don't ignore me, Bocchi-chan!
It's me, Big Sister Kikuri!
I shouldn't have invited her!
Get it together, loser!
S-Senpai... Uncle, uncle!
31st Annual Shuka Festival
We're Kessoku Band, and we
mainly play outside of school.
We hope our performance helps make
today more memorable for everyone.
And if you're interested, we hope
you'll come to see us at our club!
Here comes our first song...
as Kessoku Band!
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#12 Morning Light Falls on You
Watch it!