Come over now if you
wanna play hide-and-seek!
Me! I'll play!
The girl who wonders,
"Would it be okay for me to join in?"
Me! I'll play!
and so misses her chance,
ending up all alone.
Hitori-chan, what's wrong?
The girl who ends up all alone at a picnic,
Here you go.
swapping parts of her lunch with the teacher.
I'm home.
The girl who doesn't join any clubs,
comes home right after school,
And here, we'll stir-fry it a bit.
and finds her smartphone full of
nothing but messages from her parents
There's a lot of vegetables,
and coupon offers.
so you can probably make it quickly
if you cut them in advance.
That's me.
You can probably do that
in the morning, yeah.
Hitori Goto, first-year in middle school.
Lately I've gotten good at making
so many dishes so quickly
I thought I didn't need to know any more,
Sometimes I think
I should really change the way I am...
but lately I'm learning once again
how interesting cooking can be.
But I always stammer when I try to speak,
and I'm really bad at keeping eye contact...
A life as the archetypal introvert
just seems to fit me best.
Personally I like a lot of options with rice.
Oh, of course. But you—
You watching this?
Nah.
Back in school, I was the guy who sat in the
back of the classroom pretending to read.
No friends.
And now you're part of a band that's
extremely popular with young people!
Yeah. A band is a place where
even introverts can shine.
I see!
Now, here's "Trigger" by Instorms!
What is it?
D-Dad, can I use your guitar?
Sure!
Th-Thanks!
Aha!
At last, Hitori's getting into guitar too!
Maybe even someone like me can shine
if I'm in a band!
I've made up my mind.
I'm gonna learn to play guitar!
My First Electric Guitar
Then I'll form a band at school, and...
Master the Low Chords
*Commonly Used Major Chords
E, A, G...
What's with all the English?
Then I'll play at the culture festival
and have everyone go crazy for me!
3 Years Later
Crazy... for me?
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#01 Lonely Rolling Bocchi
I practiced six hours every day, so I could
learn how to play in front of people...
The result?
Middle school ended, and I
never played a single note for them!
Congrats on Graduating!
I never performed once...
98th Annual Graduation Ceremony
At the culture festival!
I never put together...
The members for a band!
And I never made a single friend...
In three whole years!
Now, in high school...
Graduation
Yokohama Genseiryo Middle School
I gotta form a band or die trying!
But despite my vow, it's been a whole month
since high school started,
and yet my heart remains
grounded in the guitar,
little better than a shut-in...
Lyrics and music by me.
From the closet with love.
But before I cause neighborhood problems
playing my crummy original song late at night,
Drag & Drop to Upload Video
Choose File
Upload Video
I've gotta upload a cover
I did of a popular band.
Uploading...
It's been a pretty long time
since I started uploading myself
playing under the name "guitarhero"
on my dad's advice, but...
Wow, my latest video already
has so many comments.
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
High school's just been way too much fun!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
High school's just been way too much fun!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views                                                        Dislike
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
High school's just been way too much fun!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
10 comments                 Sort
Add Public Comment
Pyonkichi  5 Minutes Ago
You're so good! Are you a pro by any chance? :D
Sam03  30 Minutes Ago
You rocked the chorus, love it
I've been racking up the views lately, too,
and people are telling me I'm good...
Yeah, maybe it's okay
if I can't handle real life!
There are tons of people
cheering for me online!
Sam03  30 Minutes Ago
You rocked the chorus, love it
Nekomi  5 Minutes Ago
I listen to this every day!
I just started playing guitar myself and I'm so in awe!
Can't wait for the next one!
The internet is filled with socially
anxious introverts just like me!
Deyon  1 hour ago
2:17 this part rocks
Johnson 1 hour ago
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
"I formed a band and played this for our cul—"
I put the effort in, okay?
I brought CDs to school
and set them on my desk.
Talk to me!
I bought band merch and showed it off.
I put in song requests at lunch...
This next song is a request
from Goto-san in Class 2-A.
I'm gonna...
...for the death metal song
I'd been obsessed with lately.
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna crush your skuuull!!!
Not the flashbacks!
Begone! Begone, filthy memories!
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this
for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
I wish I could perform live...
Gomachin  1 hour ago
What pedals are you using?
Kaopin  1 hour ago
I formed a band and played this
for our culture festival!
The whole school went crazy for it!
Replies
OZAKI  30 minutes ago
I played it with my band club too!
Taku  5 minutes ago
Lucky! Not sure if there's anyone at
my high school that plays guitar...
Taku  5 minutes ago
Lucky! Not sure if there's anyone at
my high school that plays guitar...
That...
That could work!
Sleep Pipe
I look... I look so cool!
I'm already a total rocker chick!
I look like a real somebody!
The people can't look away!
Someone's just gotta talk to me now!
I'm gonna be all over this
year's culture festival!
So you could see the corgi's butt...
Do we move rooms next period?
Science Room B.
Hey, wanna karaoke after this?
Great idea!
You sure?
Wonder what I should sing...
Huh?
Did I go overboard
hyping myself up last night?
But I'm putting out such
powerful rocker chick vibes...
D-Did I end up making myself unapproachable?!
No, no, no!
I'm having a mental breakdown!
Wow, look at that!
Thump
At what?
I-If they're laughing at me now,
it won't just be a mental breakdown,
it'll be mental annihilation!
Aw, it's so cute, I've gotta laugh!
Guitar?
My day's immediately better!
Right, Kita-chan?
Kita-chan?
Sorry, sorry! What was it?
Look, I know.
You can't put the onus on others
and expect perfect results.
This is a gathering place for
people just as lonely as me.
I bet that guy's separated from—
Papa!
Sorry we're late!
Hey, no problem.
Now, let's grab dinner!
What would you like?
They're the perfect freakin' family!
Please forgive my presumptuous empathizing...
Ah. I broke 30,000 subscribers.
Hey, that's right.
The online world is where I belong.
Sorta makes me not wanna go back to school...
Guitar!
That's a guitar, right?
Do you play?!
Hello?
I-I haven't talked to anyone
in so long... my voice!
Hey, sorry to ambush you.
I'm Nijika Ijichi, second-year
at Shimo-Kitazawa High.
Hitori Goto. Shuka High. First-year.
So tell me, Hitori-chan...
Right to first names, are we?!
How good are you at guitar?
Pretty decent, I guess...
Really?!
Say, I'm in kind of a fix here...
If you can't do it, that's okay, but...
It's really okay, but I'm in a real fix...
There's nothing okay about her!
Okay, I'll come right out with it!
Please, will you play second
guitar for my band for today?!
Band?
We've got a concert coming up,
and our guitarist just split!
The song's not too hard!
You'll pick it up right away!
A concert?! Right now?!
Please! Please!
Um, err...
Thanks! Let's head to the club!
I haven't even said anything yet!
I got dragged along.
Do you come to Shimo-Kita a lot, Hitori-chan?
Oh, well...
Right, like I've got the courage to visit
a fashion town for trendy people...
We're almost to the club.
Nijika-chan's fashionable, too.
She's got the real rocker-chick vibe.
Meanwhile, I'm in a potato-quality tracksuit
with a real bear of a set of bags under my
eyes, and a back as arched as a cat...
Wait, do I also smell like mold?
I spend so much time in the closet...
No, I smell like mothballs.
Meanwhile, Nijika-chan smells great!
She smells just the way
a high school girl should!
Oh, am I walking too fast?
N-No...
The club we're gonna play at
is called Starry.
My big sister's the manager there.
Playing at a club...
That sounds weirdly legit.
Wait, what's my heart doing?
And so...
I've been working there part-time...
Hitori-chan, are you
actually pretty athletic?
N-No, but I'm always the last one standing
in dodgeball for some reason.
I... I see.
Me? Playing in a club?
No, don't back down now!
Remember your daydreams of
performing at the culture festival!
And your first solo show at Zepp Super Arena!
Hitori! Hitori! Hitori!
I'm the girl who sold out the Budokan...
What?
Oh, nothing!
Please, don't let her think she
made a mistake choosing me!
I might've made a mistake choosing her...
We're here!
This is the place!
Th-The dark lands?
Good morning!
My first club...
It's so dark... So stuffy...
I-It's so soothing!
You okay, Hitori-chan?
I'm home!
It is not!
Could we ask the PA to record again?
That's the band that's playing today.
I thought bands would be intimidating,
They might be a little older than us?
but they're all indoorsy, shy introverts!
After they're done, we'll rehearse too.
They're just like me!
That there's the PA.
No drinks on the equipment!
Good morning.
Please forgive my arrogance!
What's wrong now?!
You're finally back.
Ryo!
This is Hitori Goto. Hitori-chan!
I met her in the park by miraculous
happenstance! She's a guitarist!
Oh?
Scary! Is she glaring at me?
This is Ryo Yamada. She plays bass.
I-I'm Hitori Goto! I'm so very sorry!
Hang on!
Y-You're okay!
Ryo's just not the expressive type.
Feel free to call her weird! She likes it!
I don't, actually.
Seemed like she did...
By the way, about the manager...
She told you to practice until it was time,
but instead you snuck out of the club,
so she got so mad she went out shopping.
N-No way!
Let's be in the studio before she comes back!
You too, Hitori-chan!
C'mon!
R-Right!
Real life is scary.
But I feel like there's
some fun stuff coming up!
Here's today's set list and score.
Wh-Where are the other band members?
This is everyone!
We'll be doing all instrumentals this time.
Right. I can handle this song.
Though without any vocals, the playing's
gotta be all that much better...
But I'm supposedly good at guitar. I can do this.
I think I can do this!
Gorilla?
Maybe they'll be blown away by my playing!
I mean, I get pretty good...
pretty decent reactions online.
Let's take it right from the top.
It's your first time,
so we'll run through slow,
I even have 30,000 subscribers!
then we can speed it up
as you get used to it.
Yeah, let's do this!
Okay, let's go!
You suck!
H-How can I suck?
Ah, I'm kidding!
I'm guitarhero!
Well, not totally kidding, but...
Ah, I'm sorry!
I've got 30,000 subscribers!
Allow me to explain!
Guitar Man's
Easy-to-Learn
Hitori Classes
In a band, it's super important to be in
sync with your fellow live performers!
But Hitori has social anxiety
and can't make eye contact,
and she'll be inclined to
rush ahead of the others!
She might be an awesome solo player,
God
Social Butterfly
Normal Person
Water Flea
Hitori
but when in a band, she's sub-water-flea
level, the worst there is!
Hello. I'm Plankton Goto.
She sounds like an unfunny comedian!
And thus, Hitori Goto turned to dust,
and never picked up a guitar again.
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
THE                               END
Water Flea                Hitori Goto
Drummer                  Nijika Ijichi
Bassist                       Ryo Yamada
Guitar Man              As Himself
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
Come out, please!
The show's about to start!
I c-c-can't do it!
It's not your fault!
We just came together today!
It's not like I'm very good either.
I'm very good.
Just look at me, okay!
Stay here in reality!
It isn't like I could
do the intro or anything...
I-I could offer up my life
to put on a harakiri show!
Th-They'll at least remember
the name of the band, right?
Sorry I sucked!
That's a little too rock!
It's okay.
If they boo you, I'll give
them a bonk with my bass.
Bonk.
Does a bass make such a fancy noise?
I mean, bloodshed is pretty rock.
It's rock.
You can't justify everything with "rock"!
Besides, it'll probably just be my
friends who come to watch us play!
And Nijika is my only friend, so...
Normal high school girls
don't know good music from bad.
That kind of take could get you
in trouble on the internet.
Okay? So just chill!
I d-dunno...
I know good music from bad.
Well, you're not normal.
Hey, that wasn't a compliment.
Sorry.
But...
We can't force her.
You're right.
Sorry to push you so hard.
No, actually...
I r-really was happy you reached out to me.
I've wanted to be in a band for so long...
B-But I couldn't get the people together...
So I just upload covers
to the internet instead.
What do you usually play?
M-Mostly songs by popular bands
from the last few years,
so I could play them right away
once the band got together...
That's awesome!
It's not.
It's the reason I'm the way I am now.
Being in a band with other people
was a pipe dream after all.
Covering all popular songs?
She sounds like guitarhero-san!
Have you heard of her?
She's probably about our age, I think...
guitarhero...
[Guitar] Acid "Spring Snow" [Gave it a try]
Views: 1,012
Sorry I can't upload very often nowadays!
There's just so much going on at high school!
Next time I'll try a song I do all the time
with my friends at karaoke!
10 comments                                      Sort
M-Me?!
I'll send you a link if you haven't!
She's super awesome! You should hear her!
Awe... some?
She comes up in my recommendations
a lot, so I've seen her too.
She really is excellent.
Right?!
Though her naming sense is a bit cringy...
It is?!
I follow her with notifications on!
I'd love to play with her some day!
You just did, actually...
Look, what I'm getting at here
is that even awesome, popular people
are out there playing guitar,
lots and lots of them,
in places we're not even watching.
You should watch her later!
I think you'll get what I mean
if you watch the videos.
I always figured real-life people
didn't care about me at all...
You can't give up on playing in a band
just because it didn't work out today!
It's possible it's our problem, anyway...
Our problem?
Hitori-chan?
But someone this nice has been
watching me all this time,
and actually spoke to me...
She stood up.
It's the kind of miracle
most people never experience!
I can't let it go to waste!
I... I'm...
D-Do you want to perform after all?
Hitori-chan?
I know all that, rationally...
But I'm still too scared...
There's no way I can play
in front of an audience...
If you're scared,
you could play from in here.
Ripe Mangos
I-It's the same environment
that I play in all the time!
Where exactly do you live?
Ripe Mangos
How you feelin' tonight, Shimo-Kita?!
She's suddenly more outgoing.
By the way, how do you
want us to introduce you?
"Hitori-chan"? Should we use your real name?
I'd... I'd rather not...
Any nicknames, then?
In middle school, they called me
"Hey" and "You there"...
I don't think those are nicknames!
I never knew anyone well enough
to get nicknames from them!
Hitori...
Hitoribocchi (all alone)...
How about Bocchi-chan?
Another tactless comment!
I'm B-B-Bocchi!
She likes it?
It's just my first ever nickname...
This is making me teary-eyed.
Oh, you haven't told me your band name yet.
It's Kessoku Band.
Kessoku Band...
Isn't that the word for "zip tie"?
It's brilliant.
It's the worst pun!
We're totally changing it!
Why? It's cute.
Y-Yes.
Band name aside, it's time to play!
Don't worry.
The key is to have fun, even if you suck!
Your feelings really come
out in your playing, see?
R-Right...
We can always work on the
skill part next time.
Yeah.
Next... time...
Okay, let's go!
Right.
They're okay with there being a next time!
Nice to meet you! We're Kessoku Band!
We'll play a bunch of
songs you probably know,
so please enjoy!
Who's that?
I hate that I can't play as
well as I usually do, but...
playing in a band with other
people is so much fun!
I've never really shone before today...
And I still don't!
This might actually be a low point for me!
Boy, I screwed up!
Your intro bombed, too.
E-Excuse me!
B-B-B...
What?
B-B-B-B-B...
Okay, you're freaking me out!
B-Before our next performance, I'm gonna get
brave enough to say hello to my classmates!
What a dramatic declaration.
Such growth...
Okay, I get it.
Sure!
Then let's have a Bocchi-chan-welcome-party-
slash-concert-post-mortem!
Actually, I'm pretty exhausted from
all this social interaction, so I'm gonna go.
Sorry. I'm sleepy.
P-Pardon me!
There's no "ties" in this band at all!
I'm gonna get over my social anxiety
and bring out my full guitarhero powers!
For Nijika-chan,
Ryo-san,
and Kessoku Band!
S-Sorry! Sorry!
#02 See You Tomorrow
Watch it!