Kessoku Band managed to succeed
in its first full four-member concert.
And so, our summer came to...
August
a middle.
That's right. We do have
some break left, don't we?
Until my summer break comes to an end...
What lovely weather!
I'm going to spend every single day
enjoying it to its fullest.
Shake!
Another fulfilling day...
Not!
It's summer break, but I'm not
doing a single thing differently!
August
I mean, playing guitar is fun and all, but...
I was thinking Kessoku Band
might hang out together,
so I've cleared my schedule
of everything but work, but...
Of course, it's usually
clear regardless, but...
B-But keeping it clear
has a totally different feel, right?
Still, even at work, nobody
so much as suggests hanging out...
Bocchi-chan! See you at work again tomorrow!
The members of a band usually
hang out, don't they?
But I guess when we're all
available, we should be practicing...
S-Still, just for once, I'd like to...
Yeah, that's right!
Kessoku Band
Can anyone take my shift
tomorrow? I've got stuff to do ^^;
I can take it!
GRATITUDE
I can't always be passive!
B-But if I bring it up,
I'm the one who'll have to pick
the place and time...
I can't think of a plan
that'll satisfy everyone!
Nijika
But I just have to work up the courage!
I'll start with Nijika-chan!
Nijika
Message                                Mobile                             Video
Well... It's a bit late to call now.
Hitori-chan! Time to eat!
A-Anyway, there's a lot of summer break left!
I'm sure one of them will make
the offer sooner or later.
Yay!
What is the general theory of relativity?
The general theory of relativity
states that the passage of time slows
in the presence of a powerful gravity well.
Time slows due to curvature of spacetime caused by a powerful gravity well
Artist's impression of a black hole drawing in matter
The black holes theorized
to exist throughout space
are believed to be the end state
of the life cycle of massive stars.
Their extreme density and
high gravitational potential
mean that not only matter, but even light,
becomes trapped forever in their pull.
The gravitational field causes time to slow
so much that it nearly stops...
Hitori-chan! I'm coming in!
I thought I'd air out the futons
while the weather's nice.
Don't lie around all day, all right?
You'll be back at school soon.
But I'm in a black hole.
August 30th
Sis
another day
nowhere
lying around
really
funny
It's done!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#09 Enoshima Escar
Bocchi-chan? Acting strange?
Yeah.
She's been staring out into space,
and she's barely talked in days.
Sounds like typical Bocchi.
C'mon, you can't possibly...
Astaxanthin. Canthaxanthin.
...be exaggerating.
I'm not!
She seemed on the verge
of tears for a minute,
but then she spontaneously
started dancing the samba!
Tortilla!
That's not good!
Typical Bocchi.
It is not!
Hey.
Could you get Bocchi-chan to knock it off?
Eh?
She's been making cicada graves
in front of the club all day.
That's way too out there!
What's got her freaking out like that?
I wonder if it's because today's
the last day of summer break.
Farewell. Farewell.
I don't wanna go back to school either.
Say, guys.
Have you actually taken her out
anywhere this summer?
One time, while you were working, I asked
what she was doing with her time off...
Bocchi-chan. What are you doing with
your break when you're not working?
Um, I... My little sister asked me
to teach her guitar, so I did.
Hey, that's nice.
B-But...
Today I asked my sister
to teach me to play guitar!
I thought it was awesome how my sister
stayed inside practicing, day after day!
I have too many things to do and too many
friends to play with over summer break,
so I can't stay home practicing
every day like her!
That's why I think it's awesome!
H-Her words sent me into a spiral, and
I ended up not getting out of bed for days.
I see.
I cleared my schedule!
N-Not because I have nothing to do!
I cleared it on purpose!
R-Right.
She said all that.
Why didn't you tell us earlier?
I wanted to invite her, but...
My schedule's packed every day I'm not here,
and I thought she'd be uncomfortable
around people she doesn't know, so...
What about you, Ijichi-senpai?
W-Well, when we're not practicing, I'm
cleaning up at home or working here, so...
R-Ryo-senpai?
I figured you two had invited her already.
Y-You're telling me...
Nobody invited Bocchi-chan out?
You guys need to change your band name.
G-Gotoh-san! You want to hang out?
Docosahexaenoic acid. Eicosapentaenoic acid.
Come back to us!
I know! Let's all go to the
beach together, right now!
We could hit up Enoshima!
Great idea! It's a straight shot
from Shimo-Kita.
B-But...
What-about-our-practice-then?
Why's she talking like a robot?
We can practice any time!
It's not like we have our next
concert scheduled, anyway.
Let's use our last day of summer break
to make memories together!
Memories...
Isn't that a great idea?
Let's go to the beach together!
But it might be too late to swim.
Y-Yeah... no point in going to
the beach if you can't swim.
B-But there's still the beach shacks!
Let's eat shirasu-don!
And we can gaze at the ocean from the sand...
Ocean... Sand...
See? Doesn't that sound fun?
Wait for me!
You catch up!
The end of summer, huh?
Let's come again next year.
Tropical love forever!
Tropical love...
Gotoh-san!
Forever...
Why is this happening?
I think I made it worse somehow.
Okay! Let's take her out while she's docile!
Roger!
Kita-chan, you carry Bocchi-chan!
What?!
Okay! Let's get going to Enoshima!
Yeah!
Gotoh-san! We'll be making
those summer memories soon!
Just hang in there a little longer!
Scary... Tropical...
I'm in a black hole... at the
far reaches of the galaxy...
She must really hate school
to be acting this way.
Is your school super strict?
Too far for the sunshine
of summer to reach...
No, I'd say it's on the liberal side.
Trapped by the powerful gravity...
And the culture festivals are lots of fun!
Aw, lucky!
Our school's pretty strict,
and the culture festivals are super uptight.
It's mostly science project
posters and stuff.
An Observation on the
Lifecycle of the Honeybee
Phylum: Arthropoda  Class: Insecta
Order: Hymenoptera  Family: Apidae
Genus: Apis  Scientific Name: Apis
An Investigation into the Weight of
Ragworms Based on Environment
Phylum: Annelida  Class: Polychaeta
Order: Phyllodocida  Family: Nereididae
Genus: Hediste  Scientific Name: Hediste
Really?
That's right. Shimo-Kitazawa High
is a prep school, isn't it?
You two must be really smart!
I'm pretty average, myself...
And Ryo is... yeah.
Eh?
You bombed your last round of tests, right?
Yep.
Eh?
She picked the school for
the same reason I did:
because it was close to home!
Yep.
But then how did you pass the entrance exam?
Ryo's a cram-the-night-before type.
She worked really hard right before the exam,
but apparently forgot it all after.
When I study too hard,
I forget how to play bass.
Which means Ryo-senpai isn't
mysterious and thoughtful at all...
No! Her brain is so small you can hear it
rattling around in her skull!
Maybe we can use that sound in a new song!
Stop it! Stop destroying my fantasy!
Don't yell on the train.
I'm deleting this conversation
from my memory!
Is this what overly strong love does to you?
C-Curvature of spacetime...
What are you seeing right now, Bocchi-chan?
I don't get why she's so isolated at school.
She's so fun.
Right?
I wish everyone at her school
could see how cool she is.
I'll make sure to talk to her
when school starts again.
You totally should!
Bocchi-chan's dream right now
is to drop out of school!
Does that even count as a dream?!
Anyway, let's use today to make a fun
summer memory with Bocchi-chan!
Let's take a picture, Gotoh-san!
I'm gonna get some sea salt
soft-serve. See you later.
Hey! No one said this was free time!
Gotoh-san. Please wake up already!
Gotoh-san!
Look!
The beach is so big!
H-Huh?
Wh-When did I...
You've really been out cold this whole time?
Th-Thank you, Kita-san.
When was the last time I've been to the beach?
Now that I'm here,
I can see how beautiful it—
Hey, girls!
Come eat at our beach shack!
We got a discount for cuties like you!
I-It's a party animal in the flesh!
We can get you a table for four right away!
Are y'all in high school?
Where'd you come from?
Bocchi-chan exploded!
Archetypal beach bros.
They're too powerful for us to handle!
Let's get away from the beach, ASAP!
Asahi Shop
Thanks for coming.
Here, for you, Gotoh-san.
Th-Thanks...
Enoshima Fried
Tako Senbei
Asahi Shop
What is this?
Takosen!
I hear they press the takoyaki
with a full ton of force!
A ton of force?
It's good!
My tastiness sensor never fails.
V-Very impressive!
Bocchi-chan, I'm just glad
to see you feeling better!
It's so big and cute!
So photogenic!
Let's take a picture!
Okay! Here comes the selfie!
Lemme see!
It turned out super great!
I ate tako senbei with them.
Summer memories...
Th-Thank you...
Thank you for today.
It's been wonderful.
How are we at the climax already?!
And so, my summer came to an end.
We're just getting started!
Enoshima Shrine
Okay! Let's climb all the way to the top!
Stairs?
Is there anything more beautiful
than scenery you have to work to see?
No. Screw that.
Let's do it!
No!
You too, Gotoh-san!
You'll come with me, right, Ijichi-senpai?
I'm not super into it either...
Kita-chan! She's glowing more than ever!
H-How?
P-Perhaps her usually
understated extrovert aura
h-has been amplified
by the light of the sun!
It's stripped off her limiter, you mean?!
Come on! Let's do it!
Kit-aura
Hurry up, everyone!
I'm done. No more climbing.
Kita-chan's getting further
and further ahead...
I'm out!
Who cares about the view?
Not me.
Hang in there, you two.
We've only just started!
Lemme take a break first.
What'll I do with you?
You've got so much energy, Kita-chan...
E-Escar...
I th-think we can ride an escalator up!
C'mon, let's climb the stairs!
Money Added:
Purchase Price:
Change:
C
Sea Candle Set
Adult
Trip down is
by stairs only
C  (Minor)
Sea Candle Set
Elementary Student
B
Escar Full Trip
Adult
B (Minor)
Escar Full Trip
Elementary Student
It costs money?
You need to buy tickets
to the Enoshima Escar.
See, we should climb the stairs instead!
Welcome!
I... I have no money, but...
I've got some pretty good bass guitars.
I'll give you one.
Um, I don't think...
How about two?
You want three?!
You need to buy a ticket...
What a breeze!
But climbing the stairs would have
made the view so much more impressive.
Y-You'll pay me back next month, right?
I've never broken a promise in my life.
You didn't pay me back last time, though.
Sorry, Bocchi-chan!
I'll take it out of her paycheck.
You're inhuman!
We made it!
As long as we're here,
let's hit up the observation deck!
Even taking the Escar is kind of exhausting.
It was... quite a long way.
Yeah...
But being up this high
feels quite liberating.
P-Positivity wells up within me.
That's the fresh air and
magnificent view at work!
Sh-Should we take a picture together?
Yeah! Cheese!
Cheese!
They're finally getting into it.
Look! Isn't it pretty?
Yeah, sure.
Hey. Aren't you listening?
Tropical Love
Oh, sorry.
You're just so pretty
I forgot everything else!
You silly!
Miitan!
Takkun!
The observation deck!
Let's go to the observation deck!
Look at that!
The view from the observation deck
is even more fabulous!
We've really got to drink it all in!
I love air conditioning.
It's heaven.
S-Sure is.
Err, You guys?
Long, long ago, humans attempted
to build a tower to heaven
to prove themselves equal to God.
God, enraged, scrambled
the languages of humans,
and cast their lands into chaos.
Talking about the Tower of Babel?
B-But humans failed to learn
and built another tall tower like this?
Guys! The scenery!
Kita-chan got what she wanted,
so let's blow this joint.
G-Good idea.
My favorite part was the air conditioning.
You filthy indoor types!
Ryo. Weren't you eating sea salt
soft-serve earlier?
I've always got room for ice cream.
P-Please pay me back for the ice cream, too.
What should we do next?
I think we've had plenty of fun, don't you?
You think?
I feel like we need one more
memorable event...
I wanna eat shirasu-don, then!
They were sold out at the place
where we had lunch!
Nah. Too full.
Since when were you in charge?
What's that sound?
Oh, the kites?
They like to steal human food, so—
Right as we were talking about it!
You okay, Bocchi-chan?
Gotoh-san, you want my ice cream?
They're targeting Bocchi-chan!
She looks weak!
It pisses me off.
Teach her a lesson!
Even birds look down on her.
Even birds?!
Gotoh-san, you okay?
It's over.
Get lost!
Memorable event achieved.
That's not the kind of memorable I wanted!
But we can't stay out too late,
so we really should head out.
Bocchi's in bad shape, anyway.
Then how about a shrine visit
before we head home?
Enoshima Benzaiten
This shrine is dedicated to a goddess
called Myo-on Benzaiten.
She's the goddess of music
and performing arts.
I've always thought we should come here
if we ever went to Enoshima together.
We'll have to wish for
our band's future success!
Bocchi-chan.
You looked like you were wishing
pretty hard back there.
It took forever.
What were you wishing for?
I was wishing and thanking her
pretty hard too!
"Goddess, thanks for making
our concert a success.
Keep that good fortune coming!"
R-Really?
Let's get back to practice tomorrow!
Even though we don't have
a next concert scheduled!
I can't tell them...
Please, Goddess!
Turn back time to the first day of summer!
I'll do anything, just turn back time!
Either that, or give me fame and fortune
so that I never go hungry!
...that I made a really vapid wish!
It's about an hour from here
to Shimo-Kita, right?
Yeah.
Gotoh-san, you'll change
trains at Fujisawa, right?
Y-Yes.
Wake me up at Shimo-Kita.
Oh, they're hopeless!
I really wish we'd gotten to do
some Kamakura sightseeing,
and I wish we'd had dinner together, too!
Shirasu-don...
She really wanted to eat that, huh?
My first long trip in a while...
That was lots of fun.
I almost wish we could've
stayed out a little longer.
Okay!
Let's spend all of winter break
hanging out as Kessoku Band!
Where do you want to go, Gotoh-san?
Let's make memories together
every single day!
I d-don't wanna go outside every day!
I'll th-think about it...
Sure!
You can rest if you want, Gotoh-san.
I'll wake you up.
A-Actually, I spent the whole
train ride up here unconscious,
so I'm pretty alert now.
Really?
Then the fun continues until Fujisawa!
H-Hey... Kita-san?
I e-enjoyed hanging out with you all today.
I th-think I can face school
starting tomorrow.
Probably.
Really? I'm glad to hear it!
Let's enjoy the new term together, too!
Sure.
This memory of summer will fuel me
through to winter break.
Hitori-chan! It's morning!
I'm coming in!
You're still in bed?
You'll be late to school your first day back!
Don't feel good. Wanna stay home.
Oh, Hitori-chan. Lying again
just to get out of school!
N-No...
Help me out, Futari!
M-My muscles are so sore,
I can't even move!
Okay!
Wake up, Sis!
No, no, no, no!
Morning!
Hey, Kita-chan, I saw your
Issta photos of Enoshima!
31st Annual
Shuka Festival
Stage performers wanted!
October 1st & 2nd
Location: Shuka High School Gym
Please place requests for stage time
in the box in front of the student council room
prior to the deadline.
A participant interview will take place after applications are received.
Participant groups will also need to explain stage crew requirements.
Feel free to ask questions!
Application deadline: September 16th
Planning/Organization: Shuka High School
Culture Festival Executive Committee
Really? Thanks!
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
Hey, why doesn't it stop?
The rhythm that I can't stop
keeps reverberating through my body
The melody playing in my earphones
is the only thing that lets me be who I am
The sky is tinged in red
But what color is my soul?
Tell me
where should I go?
I've always been searching
for something precious (hey!)
If everything's going to be lost some day
let's engrave it as deep as we can (now!)
My most pathetic nights
and cackling laughter
And days when I couldn't say
more than "You know..."
(I'm alive now, yeah Springtime of life)
What's wrong with not
letting my sound die down?
What's wrong with being young?
#10 After Dark
Watch it!