And whipped cream up to the ceiling!
Excuse me, girls.
It's your long-awaited payday.
Yay!
Y-Yay.
Thanks!
Thank you very much.
Thank you!
Sure.
And for you, Bocchi-chan.
Th-Thank you!
T-Ten thousand yen!
10,000 Yen
The culmination of my blood,
sweat, and tears!
What'll I spend it on?
New sheet music?
Solitary Rock
by Fuyu Hamaji
A big manga haul?
Kirakira Books Meisouchuu!
by Fuyu Hamaji
Maybe I'll buy a cake and surprise my family!
Mom and Dad
Thanks For Everything
Sorry to rain on various parades,
but I've gotta collect these for the concert!
Lend me your ears.
Money
My new song, "A Farewell to Yukichi."
I'm so sorry!
I hate it too, okay?
That's right.
I'm sorry to you too, Kita-chan!
I was doing this job thing
to pay our concert quota.
Hey, it's fine!
Of course, if I work hard here every month,
Kessoku Band will get to play a lot,
which is just about—
Wow!
Does it really cost that much
to make an album?
Huh?
Yeah, I'd like to have them
to sell at our concerts,
and shooting a music video and stuff
will cost a ton, too...
We'll just have to get second jobs
during summer vacation!
Yeah.
Maybe we could work at
a beach house or something!
I'd love to work at the beach!
B-Beach?!
Ushiushi Finance
Simple Same-day Loan Questionnaire
With this simple screening process,
Ushiushi Finance offers loans
24 hours a day, 365 days a year.
Flexible payment options
Choose monthly or lump sum repayment
The safe, superior choice for financing!
If you need money, we've got your back!
Ushiushi Finance
Or maybe an amusement park!
Apply here
How a loan works
Get your Ushiushi Finance loan
in three easy steps!
1. Fill out the application form
2. A member of our staff will contact you
3. Money arrives in your account!
Apply     Callback     Quick Cash
Please Note
All necessary items on the application
page must be filled out
It's a no-go.
That would be so fun!
They won't lend to minors.
But perhaps, deeper in the
internet's shadier corners...
I'll have to sell my liver.
Bocchi.
I'm s-sure I could get a loan
using my guitar as collateral,
s-so please don't make me get another job!
P-Please don't make me work at
the beach or an amusement park!
Actually, I wrote the song.
Is it just me, or is it really good?
Yeah, it's great!
When I read Bocchi's lyrics,
it just came to me.
That's awesome!
All the hard work paid off!
That's my girl. There, there.
S-Senpai! I'm working hard, too!
Watch me!
I've gotten so good at guitar!
Amazing.
Amazing?!
Please give me chin rubs, too!
There, there.
My dream might just come true.
Okay!
I'll ask Sis to let us hold
our concert here next month!
You hadn't asked her yet?
No worries!
She let us in right away last time!
Right, Sis?
I'm not putting you on.
Huh?
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#05 Flightless Fish
Potential August Bands
• Macaroni Pencil
• Yukiguni with Tunnel
But why? We just finished our original song.
Why should I care about that?
Th-This feels super awkward...
We can even pay our quota
if we don't bring in customers!
It's not about the money.
It's about your skill.
But you let us play last time.
I made an exception so you
could make a memory.
"Make a memory"?
Normally, I'd make you play first to apply.
You know that, right?
Yeah, but...
Sorry, but I can't have a repeat
of that awful May performance.
Can't have a repeat...
You mean we...
Just stick with it as a hobby or something.
You got more to say?
You can't even sleep without
stuffed animals to cuddle!
Ijichi-senpai!
That was a weird parting shot.
Would the stuffed animals in question
be this beat-up panda and rabbit?
That's cute.
Delete that image! Immediately!
What are you doing? We have to go after her!
Don't act like it's too much trouble!
You too, Gotoh-san!
Let's go!
R-Right!
Wait, Bocchi-chan.
Y-Yes?
What, what, what?
What, what, what?!
It's so obvious when you're sulking.
Shut up.
Senpai, are you all right?
Sorry to rush out like that.
She didn't have to be such
a jerk about it, you know?
E-Excuse me!
Bocchi-chan?
E-Excuse me...
M-Manager... said...
She said...
Bocchi-chan, breathe first!
Here, Bocchi-chan!
Th-Thank you.
Feel better?
Y-Yes.
Um... The manager told me...
Potential August Bands
• Macaroni Pencil
• Yukiguni with Tunnel
• Inoue brothers
• Ryokuoushoku Yasai
• Kessoku Band
Tell Nijika.
If she wants to perform,
she needs to audition.
I'll watch the performances
next Saturday and decide...
What?
What are you doing?
I-I'm desperately attempting
to show obedience!
You should probably go after them
before you lose them.
W-Woof!
When a dog rolls over to show its belly,
some believe that's not
a show of submission,
but a show of aggression.
Ryo-senpai knows so much!
But wait a minute...
Does that mean...
An audition?!
Yeah!
And if we pass, she'll let us perform?
Y-Yes.
Well, why didn't she just
say so to begin with?
That sister of mine is so mean!
But that means we just have to work hard!
Isn't that nice?
Yeah, that's right.
You've got that "those two are the
biggest problem" look on your face.
Erk!
Erk
We'll record your parts in advance,
so just practice miming along!
Right!
No! No air guitars!
We've only got a week.
Don't push them so hard.
Even if they suck, the passion
will come through if they try!
We suck?
Oh, sorry!
You're really both way
better than you were.
Right, Ryo?
C'mon, back me up here!
B-Bocchi-chan?
Please don't turn into a pipe shut-in!
S-Sorry for my momentary arrogance
over my success in writing lyrics.
sorry for my momentary arrogance over my success in writing lyrics those with uncontrollable arrogance deserve a life inside a dark dank pipe.
Ah, it's The Sound of Bocchi!
Those with uncontrollable arrogance
deserve a life inside a dark, dank pipe.
Huh?
They think she isn't good?
Gotoh-san?
At least when I heard her at school before,
even I could tell as a novice
that she's really good.
C'mon, come out now!
Please just come out!
If I could remove myself
from your memory, I would...
Was that just dumb luck before?
So long as the rhythm section's strong,
it'll probably work out.
Y-You think?
Yeah!
I don't think they need to see us
all playing on Ryo's level.
Th-Then what do they need to see?
Hmm... enthusiasm? Growth as a band?
Growth?
Gotoh-san, thank you.
For practicing with me.
I-It's nothing...
But shouldn't we practice in a classroom
instead of this dreary place?
Oh, w-well, actually...
How am I supposed to practice with
all those judging eyes asking,
"What's a cool girl like Kita
doing with that loser?!"
Oh, I get it!
You don't want to bother people
by playing in a classroom!
You're so considerate, Gotoh-san!
She always assumes my motivations are pure!
What a nice person!
Hey, Gotoh-san...
I've been thinking about it.
I think we just need to show
that we've grown as a band—
in other words, how hard we've been working.
R-Right.
When the time comes, I want to
be able to say I gave it my all,
and that I don't have any regrets.
So please stick with me until
the day of the audition!
P-Please don't bow!
I-I'm the one who's h-happy to be here!
What's with the hair?
What are we doing?
"V-Visually showing our growth
as a band"... Apparently.
More of Ryo's mischief?
Drinking, smoking, dalliances with women,
and the mop-top hairstyle...
It all equals "band."
You're laying it on a little thick!
And no smoking or drinking
until you're twenty!
Everyone say, "mop-top"!
Nijika.
Gotten it out of your system?
We've got an opening for
"uneven bangs that hide one eye
and a perpetually annoyed expression."
I'll pass, thanks.
U-Um...
I c-can't have dalliances with women.
I d-don't think any women
would want to dally with me...
Don't worry.
Stand in front of VillePan in Shimo-Kitazawa,
wearing your guitar and looking listless,
and someone'll come up to you
sooner or later.
Cut it out!
Stop misinforming her with
your subjective experience!
Let's do it right!
But growth isn't always visible.
And the criteria is quite vague.
No, it's very clear!
We just need to convince Sis to take us on!
Practice is the only way!
Now, get changed!
You too, Kita-chan!
R-Right!
I think I get what Ryo-san's saying, though.
It's hard to know exactly
what "growth" means.
Ow!
I don't think it's quite the same
as effort put in.
My life as of late has been a whirlwind.
I started working.
I've gained the ability to occasionally
look others in the eye.
Your finger's looking better.
But I don't think that's the same thing
as growing as a band.
I've just evolved past the
water flea or euglena stage
and now stand at the starting line
of basic humanity.
I thought finally starting
the band I dreamed about
would be growth in itself, but...
I...
Okay, let's call it a day.
Already?
Yeah.
Get a good night's rest
for the audition tomorrow.
See you.
Great work, all!
Bocchi-chan!
Sorry, sorry!
Didn't mean to startle you.
I-It's okay.
Cola, right?
Wh-Wh-What? Yes?
Here!
Th-Thank you.
Sorry if I forced you to go along with this.
I mean, you kind of just got roped into
joining Kessoku Band from the start, right?
I remember you saying...
you'd been wanting
to be part of a band,
but I never actually asked you what
kind of band you wanted to be in,
or what your reasons were
for playing in this band now.
Oh, well...
Should I tell her I started because
I wanted people going crazy for me?
Everyone's got their own reasons, right?
It's not like performing live
is the only way to go now.
You can always post videos and stuff nowadays
if what you want is to get your sound out there.
It's true.
[Guitar]Clear ghost encount "Thanks for the Yogurt" [Gave it a try]
I like uploading as guitarhero too,
Views       103k                         Dislike
I love my new job working at a music club!
I'm super busy with showing my kohai the ropes!
Here I'm trying a song by an artist a new friend of mine
introduced me to! The mistakes in the solo
are part of the charm!
Yoshio Mania  30 minutes ago
Not sure when I last heard someone playing so clean?
Amazing! You've got such confident chords,
and very few picking mistakes.
182 comments          Sort
Add Public Comment
mou rock  2 hours ago
I love that neroooom sound in the chorus.
Please tell me what equipment you're using.
Aichi  1 hour ago
I don't know the song but now I love it
Shindo Goh 2 hours ago
Need to do a face reveal soon.
I want to see you everywhere.
Blossom day  2 hours ago
and I have to admit that the
online world suits me well...
Aoi  30 minutes ago
Pleased to meet you!
You were super cool! Are you a prodigy?
Your timbre is so clean and polished...
And I bet you're cute, too (thinks
Papa Mikan  1 hour ago
Awesome! You're super awesome!!
Aoharu Channel 3 hours ago
Great job!!!
Instant subscribe for that talent!
Aoi  30 minutes ago
Pleased to meet you!
You were super cool! Are you a prodigy?
Your timbre is so clean and polished...
I bet you're cute, too (just my imagination).
Papa Mikan  1 hour ago
Awesome! You're super awesome!!
Aoharu Channel 3 hours ago
Great job!!!
Instant subscribe for that talent!
See... I've got this kind of goal.
A dream, really.
So I can get a little fired up
without realizing it.
So... I worry I might have dragged you
into this against your will.
N-N-Not at all!
It's n-n-not against my will at all!
Really? That's good.
The reason you wanted a band...
It's to get famous and perform
at the Budokan, right?
My real dream is actually a little past that.
But I can't tell you just yet!
Anyway, see you tomorrow!
Day of the Audition
I spent all night thinking about my reason
for playing in this band now.
We're Kessoku Band.
We're going to play our song,
"Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet"!
I do still want to become popular
and have everyone go crazy for me...
But now... it's not just for me.
It's the four of us!
A sudden evening shower falls
And yeah, it figures,
I don't have an umbrella...
Who cares how the sky's feeling, anyway?
When it's time for the seasons to change
I never figured out what
it means to have "growth."
What are you supposed to wear? Who knows?
Spring and fall... yeah, where'd they go?
But right now, what I want
is to stay with this band and
have people go crazy for us!
The pressure of information, suffocating
A spiral of vertigo
I want to make Nijika-chan's
actual dream come true.
Don't know where I am
I can hear myself breathing
so loud, so loud...
So... I can't afford to blow this audition!
But why? I can't hear the
sounds of the world...
I don't want the band to end just yet!
It's not enough, not enough,
No one knows I'm here
I screamed when I couldn't
make a scribble of a sound
Who am I supposed to show "just who I am" to?
So I'm singing just like the fool I am
Let's lay it all out to the stars!
Thank you for having us!
Pretty good.
Or so I'd like to say, but...
Drums, you're too tense.
Guitars, you're both looking down too much.
Bass, you're too holed up
in your own little world.
Still... I think I know what
kind of band you are now.
Thank you... for the feedback.
Huh? What's with that reaction?
W-Well... I mean...
I'm saying, I learned what
kind of band you are!
This is the part where you cheer.
I think she's saying you passed.
That's what I said! You passed!
Sis, you're so misleading!
Y-You mean... we did it?
We did it!
She says we passed!
Yes!
We really did it?
Ryo, did you catch it?
Gotoh-san, we did it!
Y-Yes!
It hasn't been long, but Bocchi-chan's
playing is so different.
Gotoh-san!
Yes!
You were really incredible there, Gotoh-san.
E-Excuse me, Kita-san!
Gotoh-san?
Saitama Prefecture
Takizawa Dam
One Moment, Please
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
Gotoh-san?!
Toyama Prefecture
Kurobe Dam
Iwate Prefecture
Yuda Dam
Nagano Prefecture
Misogawa Dam
Did we just imagine that performance?
Need a glass of water?
S-Sorry.
Too many new things at once put
my stomach acid into overdrive...
Hey, you're okay!
Of course your stomach's
freaked out a little!
I can't believe we passed!
I knew it from the start.
I've even thought up our next song.
Awesome!
That's my senpai!
Well, easy to say after it's done.
Let's all take a picture!
C-Can't I clean the floor first?
She really is good.
But she's so inexperienced
playing with a team
that her lack of self-confidence
holds her back.
She could grow even more.
Huh?
Has the manager been making
eye contact with me?
To give her confidence,
she needs to know someone out there
acknowledges her talent.
She's looking at me! Is she mad?!
Because I let victory make me arrogant?
Hey, kid.
I see you, okay?
She's watching me!
Hey, Gotoh-san!
Let's take our picture!
It's over.
Manager.
Admit it. You liked them from the start.
C'mon, you've been keeping a window open
in the concert schedule for them.
Why tease them like that?
I wasn't teasing.
I just didn't want to put them on
until they were ready.
But while they're still
rough around the edges,
I think they've got something.
As her sister, I need to be hard on her
to make sure her band grows.
Is this what they call a sister complex?
One more word about that, and you're fired.
Right.
Okay! Let's work even harder to level up
our band in the lead-up to the concert!
Right!
Bocchi, I'm looking forward
to the new lyrics.
R-Right!
Isn't this getting exciting, Gotoh-san?!
Y-Yes!
Th-That's right! It's not over at all!
In fact, Kessoku Band's journey
is just getting started!
Now, since the ticket quota is twenty at
1,500 yen each, that means we each sell five!
Five-ticket quota...
Five-ticket quota?!
Five tickets, right?
Got it!
Five-ticket quota?!
Father...
My daughter's inscribing
her name into rock history...
Mother...
I'll cook some red rice!
Sister...
You're awesome, Sis!
Dog...
Woof!
Rock! Red rice! Awesome! Woof!
Father, mother, sister, dog!
I-I... I h-have one left over!
Gotoh-san is so happy, she's crying!
We have to put on a great concert together!
Yeah.
I-It's really over this time.
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can't beat that feeling
of being loved, it's true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It's time to take that step
Though there's nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It's time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I've been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I'm going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#06 Eight Views
Watch it.