31st Annual Shuka Festival
We can blame it all on the weather
All this awkwardness and exhaustion
The sun hides away, pretending not to see
A packed train clatters along the track
It brushes past a local express
I'm gonna search for feelings
in a shapeless cloud
The test asks, "How was
the author feeling here?"
What could the right answer possibly be?
Breaking through the script
of pre-established harmony
Everyone talks about the
"springtime of life"
And I'm just not cut out for that
Yet I know that this moment,
which will never come again,
is rich with evanescence
I will never forget, ever
So many times before I die someday...
I'll laugh thinking about what it was like
I feel like the wind's leaving me behind
So I'm desperately clinging on
That familiar sound of the bell
Butler Cafe
That dust piled up on the window sill
Even the smell of the classroom
I will never forget, ever
So many times before I die someday...
I'll laugh thinking about what it was like
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#12 Morning Light Falls on You
Thank you!
That was our first song,
"I Will Never Forget!"
I can't believe how enthusiastic they are.
Kita-chan!
But...
You were so cute!
Now, before we play our next song...
Let's have a few words from
Kessoku Band's leader:
our drummer and my senpai, Nijika Ijichi!
Nice to meet you, everyone!
Are you having a good time?!
They've worked pretty hard.
Yeah...
But Bocchi-chan...
Our esteemed bassist, Ryo Yamada,
told me that any MCing I did for
Kessoku Band would be a flop,
and at first I thought, "How dare you!"
But until I learn to be
entertaining with this stuff,
I figured I'd stick to concert announcements!
Of course, I don't actually know
when our next concert'll be...
But if you wanna see more,
just hit up our vocalist, Kita-chan,
Kita-chan!
or our guitarist, Bo—
Hitori Gotoh, when you can!
Hitori-chan!
Anyway, let's move on to the next song!
Right!
Please lend us your ears!
Our next song is
"To Become a Constellation..."!
The time's almost six
The evening star's already out there
Walking home, stepping on shadows
I'm hoping to blend into the night
Yeah, something's not right.
Lucky you, lucky you
It's been fine this whole time,
Must be nice to have everyone love you
but now I can't get the E string in tune...
"No, I've always been alone."
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
On a night of falling stars,
I make that moment's wish
The E string!
Not good...
But if I can at least get
the B string in tune...
A sparkling, twinkling,
trembling signal up high
The peg's broken!
She can't use the B string now.
She won't be able to do her solo.
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
What'll I do?
My solo's coming up...
The kind that people point to in the sky
If our big culture festival performance
fails because I had equipment trouble...
Don't let these lines
that link us come undone
What do I do?
What do I do, what do I do,
what do I do, what do I do?!
No matter how brightly I shine
Kita-san...
She's ad-libbing completely on the fly!
I'm going to make sure everyone can see...
how amazingly cool Gotoh-san really is!
What's their guitarist doing?
Dunno, but it's pretty awesome!
Who whips out the bottleneck
playing at a time like this?
Now it won't matter
if she's a little out of tune!
We met each other, so far away
And because it's our karma,
we'll meet again and again
In the gaps between the clouds
If only I could become
a constellation with you...
As night falls, I dream that unlikely dream
Not quite a full moon
But still lighting up the dark
I want to become a constellation with you
The kind that puts out many-colored light
I won't let these lines
that link us come undone
No matter how brightly you shine
Well... I wasn't going to
say anything before our last song,
but please let me say one thing!
Thanks so much for having us today!
We're gonna try our best
to become so good,
that one day you'll brag
about having seen us here!
Awesome!
Budokan-bound!
You were great, Whatever-san!
You did good
even when your string broke!
Hey, Gotoh-san!
Looks like you've gotta say something!
P-People with social anxiety can't talk
without a pre-arranged script!
Go! Go!
Hitori
If you put me in this unplanned situation...
Say something funny. Something funny.
Something... Something... funny...
Gotoh-san?
Kessoku Band
Gotoh-san?!
You okay, Bocchi-chan?!
Someone call a teacher!
You're a legendary rock star!
Bocchi-chan rocks!
At least show a little concern!
Seriously!
Someone bring a stretcher!
Hitori! You okay?!
I'm sorry about my sister.
H-Hey, it's fine!
It's all over.
Are you all right, Gotoh-san?
Are you conscious?
Y-Yeah...
Thank goodness.
Looks like it wasn't too bad.
Um...
I'm really sorry I ruined everything.
After all you did...
Actually, I think people liked it even more.
Um... Where are the others?
They're cleaning up now.
They said we'd have an after-party
if you were feeling well enough.
But if you aren't, we can save it for later.
R-Right...
Oh, that was a surprise.
Kita-san. You got so good so fast.
Only for rhythm, of course.
Um...
I can't do the kind of playing
that really draws people in.
But I seem to be pretty good
at the give-and-take with you guys.
I'm gonna keep working on my playing,
so please keep teaching me.
Gotoh-sa—
Hitori-chan.
R-Right!
Okay, I'm off!
Come by when you're ready!
R-Right...
I'm going to become good enough
to support Hitori-chan.
The 31st Annual Shuka High School
Culture Festival will now come to an end.
After-party! After-party!
I hope Bocchi-chan's okay...
Area ahead
off limits
Bro look, it's carti.. 🥶
Bruh, ur right lmao
Some day...
Some day, I will gtfo of high school!
Forgive me, Father!
What're you doing, Sis?
I broke the guitar Dad lent me
while we were playing!
P-Please, get up! I'm really not mad!
Please?
It's just a broken peg, right?
It's really not that big a deal.
But...
Plus, it was pretty rad the way
you broke it in the middle of the concert!
Nowadays, they sell guitars
designed to break.
You should use one of those in your next gig!
What kind of daughter
are you trying to raise?
Anyway, this is probably a good opportunity
for you to buy your own guitar.
Play with me, Dad!
What a good idea!
C'mon, Dad!
That way, if you hit an issue like this again,
you can deal with it right away.
But... Even though I do have a job,
all the money goes to my quotas.
I can't afford...
No worries!
You've got money!
Wh-Where'd it all come from?
Dad, are you involved
in some crack dealings?!
I c-can't accept your money!
We're not that badly off!
That's money you earned from
advertisements on your videos.
See, if a video gets enough views,
they pay you.
Did you forget the video site account
you use is a family account?
You mean, my videos...
We know all about 'em!
guitarhero, right?
They've been racking up the views,
so I monetized 'em in secret.
How'd my girl get so good?!
I figured you'd need the money eventually.
And it's been amazing
to see you work so hard
and get better and better at the guitar.
Right, dear?
Yes.
I don't know much about music,
but I do think you're amazing at it!
Dad... Mom...
guitarhero
This song's been a big hit
with all my friends lately!
I sing this all the time at karaoke!
The chorus gets everyone sooo hype!
o(^v^)o
My boyfriend loves this song!
Of course, it's balanced out
by my sadness at seeing you
get better and better at lying...
Barf!
There's 300,000 yen here.
I never imagined getting such a windfall.
If I buy a guitar that costs 100k,
I'll have 200k left...
And if I put that all to quota costs,
I could play for almost two years
without having to work a normal job!
Yes!
I'm totally quitting!
Bocchi-chan's been unusually chipper today.
And she bows at me
every time we make eye contact.
The thought of quitting my job fills me
with a mysterious and overwhelming power!
Time to talk to the manager now!
Ultra super Bocchi-chan?
What's this about your job?
I... W-Well... S-See...
I'll continue to work my hardest
and most earnestly at it.
What's with the sudden
declaration of commitment?
There's nothing harder than
declaring you're gonna quit a job.
Maybe I should ghost them...
But they do know where I li—
Uh, I mean, I don't want to put them out...
Bocchi-chan!
You're going to the
music shop today, right?
Maybe if I buy an instrument
for the manager, she'll let me quit!
I've got lots of money now, after all!
Bocchi-chan?
H-Hey... Could you ask the manager
if there's anything she wants?
Bocchi-chan asked that.
Since your birthday's coming up,
maybe she's talking about a present?
I don't want anything.
She says no thanks!
I'm finished.
Bocchi. I'd like a Dingwall and new Le Fay
headless and a Darkglass amp head.
We're heading to the music shop, everyone!
Let's la go!
Bocchi-chan's really nice.
Have fun!
But I prefer my presents to be a surprise.
Funder
Guitars
Internet
Electric
Guitar
Shop
Musical
Instruments
If you wanna buy an instrument,
you gotta go to Ochanomizu!
Hey, Hitori-chan!
Do you know why there are
so many music shops here?
Well, you see...
The music business flourished here
due to it playing host in the Meiji Period
to Japan's oldest professional orchestra,
leading to the formation
of now-legacy stores in Ochanomizu
like Shimokura Music,
Ishibashi Music, and etc etc, lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Vestibulum lobortis ipsum ac elit eleifend, eu maximus erat ultrices. Etiam pellentesque eu ante quis ultricies. In fringilla lacus ipsum, ut viverra ex vestibulum at. Nunc lectus lacus, vestibulum et aliquam nec, rutrum at ante. Sed mattis erat eget vulputate ornare. Morbi venenatis nisl eget nisl sagittis, sed mollis lacus faucibus. Proin imperdiet, leo at lobortis tristique, ex nisl fermentum leo, ac viverra lorem lorem nec augue. Aenean tincidunt orci at odio dapibus fermentum. Pellentesque habitant morbi tristique senectus et netus et malesuada fames ac turpis egestas....
I bet we'll be seeing a lot of this today.
Let's go in here! It's got a great selection!
I'd really rather not.
I was gonna just buy one online, but...
Ordering online is fine and all,
but you really oughta handle
a guitar before you buy it!
R-Right...
Music store owners are scary,
and if one were to start talking to me...
You like that guitar?
You got good taste, dearie.
You like Western music?
Wait, you don't?!
Time to die!
If I put on headphones
like I'm listening to music,
maybe no one will talk to me!
M-Manager! A major headbanger
has entered the store!
Must be a hardcore metal fan!
Ma'am! The heavy metal guitars
are on the second floor!
What a cute strap!
This color would look great
with your guitar, Kita-chan!
Look at all the kinds of picks!
Maybe I'll turn some into earrings!
What a great idea!
What's the matter, ma'am? Ma'am?
Can we stop by a hobby shop after this?
Plus, I checked in advance and found out
there's a nice café nearby!
Ma'am?!
Look at the damn instruments.
Excuse me.
Can I try out this bass?
Go ahead.
You're buying another, Senpai?
No.
I just like how it looks,
so I'd like to play it a bit.
Ah, is slapping okay?
Yes, that's fine.
Like this.
Is she going to be the next Davie504?
Amazing.
I didn't even go that hard.
What a great bASS!
When you go all-out but act smug about it!
Not that I mind.
What is it, Ikuyo?
You like that guitar?
No, it's not like that...
I've still got the guitar
you lent me, after all!
You can never have too many guitars.
They're all having so much fun.
Is this the lonely drummer thing
I see in manga all the time?
M-Maybe I'll buy a guitar and a bass myself!
Just to play, darn it!
I see. Were you feeling lonely?
Let's hit up a drum shop next time!
There's one in Akiba.
This one's cool...
Yamaha's pretty great, huh?
That one's custom-made, too.
It's a really great guitar,
especially for the price!
Would you like to try it out?
Um... Um...
If it's your first guitar, you might
want shielding and a mini amp!
I...
I'll take the lot.
You already have that stuff, Bocchi-chan!
Oh, you already play? I'm so sorry!
Hey, that's okay.
Her guitar broke recently,
so she's looking for a replacement.
Right, Hitori-chan?
As an AI language model, I am unable to physically interact with objects. However, I can provide information and guidance based on descriptions or specifications provided.
Lots of people have multiples nowadays.
Even students!
Oh, really?
You like this guitar, Hitori-chan?
(As an AI language model, I don't have personal preferences or the ability to physically touch objects. However, I can provide information and assistance about guitars based on your inquiries.)
She'll take this guitar, please!
Right, Hitori-chan?
As an AI language model, I cannot physically retrieve items. However, if you provide the model of the desired guitar, I can assist in locating it or providing information about it.
Thank you so much!
Bocchi's like a ventriloquist dummy.
I thought she'd matured a lot lately,
But I guess she still
has some ways to go.
I'm so glad.
I've been doing checks and
maintenance on this guitar myself.
It's really well made. I like it a lot.
I'm sure the guitar's happy
that it's going with you, too.
Thank you for coming!
Th-Thank you for having me!
M-Ma'am?!
You forgot your guitar!
How desperate was she to get out of here?
Here!
The manager wants you
to come by again some time.
R-Right. Sorry...
I'm really glad you found a good guitar!
R-Right.
What now? Wanna grab food first?
We're done.
Got something else to do?
Bocchi. You want to play your guitar
as soon as possible, right?
Hey! Stop having a telepathic
connection, you two!
Hey, it's no big deal.
I know!
Want to rent a studio
and try out your new guitar?
Ah, I'd rather not...
We'll all get to practice
together tomorrow, anyway.
We'll save the fun for then!
R-Right.
The culture festival is behind us.
We'd better start thinking
about our next concert, right?
That's right!
Write us lots of new songs, Ryo!
Just waiting for inspiration to strike.
Let me know if there's anything I can do!
Anything?
Kita-chan! Don't say that to Ryo
unless you're ready to follow through!
You can start by treating me to gyudon.
Sis! Hurry up or you'll be late!
A-Awesome...
I'm s-sorry! I haven't f-forgotten you!
Forgive me!
She's at it again.
Be back later.
My First
Another day at the job.
Illustration by Aki Hamaji
Thanks for watching!
Thank you!
The Season 2 will be on...