Commuter IC supported here
So hot!
Summer's in full swing, huh?
Very much so!
I think we're almost at Gotoh-san's house.
Great!
Thanks for showing me around, by the way.
Not at all! I'm really
looking forward to this!
Yeah! It'll be such a new experience!
I mean, we mainly only get
together at Starry, right?
Yes!
I wonder what Gotoh-san's house is like!
She said something about a cramped
cardboard box reminding her of home...
A house like a cardboard box?
Bocchi-chan says the funniest things, huh?
I can't wait!
Neither can I!
I brought some sweets and a movie I like.
Hey! You didn't forget why
we're doing this, did you?
No, I remember!
We're designing T-shirts
for our concert, right?
Yeah!
I wish Ryo-senpai could've come too...
I did invite her, but...
She says her grandma
took a turn for the worse.
Is she all right?!
Oh, she's fine.
This is like the tenth critical time
for her grandma this year.
I love the way the guitar comes in here.
You mean...
I mean, at least her grandma really exists.
That's a heckuva low bar.
Let's hang out!
Once, when some classmates invited
her to hang out with them...
Sorry, my dog Pe'z has to have surgery.
sob sob sob
What?!
So she said, but she's never even had a dog.
She hasn't?
She hasn't!
Then there's "I just got a call from
my twin sister separated at birth,"
and "my dad was in a car crash,
and now he has amnesia."
Just all the silliest excuses...
I'm impressed by how easily she comes up
with such a wide range of lies.
Senpai's amazing!
I love me a bad girl!
That's a serious Ryo obsession right there.
We're here! This is it!
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
This... is it, isn't it?
It... does say "Kessoku Band," right?
Did she mention her house was a ryokan?
I'm not sure. It just looks like
a normal house to me.
Yeah.
Anyway...
We're here, Bocchi-chan!
Hello!
C-Coming!
Sergeant For a Day
Y-Yaaaay!
W-W-Welcome!
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#07 To Your House
Sergeant For a Day
Are you having fun, Bocchi-chan?
Y-Yeah...
I b-b-bombed...
Isn't that nice?
Gotoh-san's made it clear how much
she's been looking forward to this too!
Kita-san knows the kindest words
to soothe my bombed soul.
C-Come in.
Okay!
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
Coming in!
Gotoh-san, these are for you.
Please enjoy them with your family.
Wh-What?
Th-Thank you...
Ah, t-trendiness emanates from the bag!
shining
Trendy
smells so good
I brought a movie, too!
I told you, we have to figure out
our T-shirt design for the concert!
Rather than just wearing whatever,
wouldn't having matching outfits
create a sense of one-ness?
A sense of band-ness?!
Am I wrong here?
Ripe Mangos
Besides...
There's nothing tying you guys together.
I know that's what she'll say!
You get it? We're not here to play around!
Th-This way...
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
I-I'm sorry. I'll put it all away.
W-Well, we could play around a little!
Yes, I'd love that!
W-Well then, I'll fetch the drinks.
Please make yourselves at home.
Thanks!
But wow, she really went
all-out with the decorations!
There's nothing here besides the guitar
and effects unit, though.
Yeah...
I just assumed her room would have
a bit more of a rock feel to—
Sealed
Is this... rock? 🤨
Yeah, it's pretty rock!
I w-wonder if there's
anything else rock about i—
Ow!
Bruh? Why does she have so
many copies of our ProPho?
Sealed Sealed Sealed
I don't know what's going on,
but it seems pretty darn rock!
She's got blown-up ones too!
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
She had this picture stuck up
all over her room.
She said she really liked it!
But Mom told her to take them down
because they were hurting her eyes.
And we put those seals up
when Sis was possessed before!
That should just about cover it!
Wait, are you Gotoh-san's sister?
Yes! A pleasure to meet you.
I'm Futari Gotoh.
The dog's Jimihen.
I hope barley tea's okay.
Or would they prefer a trendier drink?
So cute!
Sorry to keep you guys wa—
Hey, will you play the
Munions song on guitar?
I'll practice so I can do it
the next time I come by.
You gotta! When's the next time you come by?
I-Is this...
Jimihen's a friendly little guy!
Th-They're getting along so well,
there's no room left for me...
Huh? Bocchi-chan?
Gotoh-san?
A five-year-old and a dog
have better social skills than me.
Sis is frozen up again.
F-Futari. Wh-What are you doing here?
Wh-Where are Mom and Dad?
Shopping.
I-I-I've got grown-up things to talk about,
so please go play with Jimihen.
Aw, no fun!
I don't mind having Futari-chan here.
Yeah, same!
Y-Y-Y-You can't!
I c-c-can't whoop it up if my sister's here!
Bocchi-chan, you've been
whooping it up with us all this time?
I beg of you!
Please go play with Jimihen!
You can have an ice pop from the freezer.
Well, it is what it is!
You've got such a sisterly bond!
How did you get that
from what just happened?
Now, let's design those T-shirts!
Let's Draw
Feel free to use these!
Okay!
Okay...
We could just slap
our logo on there,
but I'd love to sell the shirts as merch, too!
N-Nijika-chan is so hungry for merch!
So if you have any other great ideas,
I might use those as well!
Okay! Let's do our best, Gotoh-san!
R-Right!
I have to impress the others for once!
C'mon, take that stuff off
before you try to look serious!
What? They really came?
Really? fr?
fr!
These friends aren't just the imaginary kind?
fr fr!
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
All done!
Let me see!
Win it
Go for it!
Kessoku
Band
Together,
let's seize
the flower
of victory!
The concept is friendship,
effort, and victory!
It's not a dang sports festival!
Aw, but I think it's cute!
Hang on. What are we winning at?
I'm not sure how "victory"
applies to a concert...
Um... vibes!
Vibes?
I just think wearing these would
really get us feeling like a unit!
Right, Gotoh-sa—
C-Class unity...
Bocchi-chan!
Is the idea of a sports festival
that traumatic for you?!
Sports Festival
The sports festival:
the number one-source of
school trauma for introverts.
School Trauma Sources for Introverts
1st Place
Parentheses, based on Japanese Introvert
Society poll, close parentheses.
(Based on Japanese Introvert Society Poll)
A heinous ritual in which those
with no athletic ability are shunned,
and even their right to exist
is stripped away.
Not only during school hours,
but afterward too,
they are forced to perform slave labor,
creating banners and practicing cheers!
One for all! All for one!
Class Unity
An entire month's torturous existence
living for naught but the sports festival!
One for all! All for one!
Class Unity
Welcome to Chez Gotoh
Looks like Gotoh-san melted.
It sure is hot today!
This way to
School Festival
No cooperation, no life!
But the true terror lurking
behind every sports festival...
Wow, this week's Bocchi Time lasted
through the whole commercial break!
Did I do something wrong?
You've really put your foot
in it now, Kita-chan!
What? Come back, Gotoh-san!
No cooperation, no life!
A place in which introverts
are constantly underfoot,
but if they just sit quietly in a corner,
they're persecuted for
not being team players!
Death to those who bring down
the sports festival mood!
No cooperation, no life!
See? They really exist!
Hello!
Thanks for having us!
Isn't it wonderful?
I never imagined Hitori
would have real friends over!
Eat your fill, all right?
Sure!
Thanks so much!
You let Hitori join your band, right?
Yes.
We didn't exactly "let" her join.
I asked her to join, and she
was willing to humor me.
Really?
See? Music really brings people together!
Right, Jimihen?
She doesn't cause too much trouble with her
retreats into her own little world, does she?
Aw, that's no trouble at all!
Yeah! It's fun!
Nice to hear.
Here, it's done.
The fact that I'm still
upset about school festivals
makes me realize I'm a downer even more,
which made everything worse...
Karaage's done!
Wow, that looks good!
That one is soy sauce with garlic,
and this one is shio koji.
And there's lemon and
shichimi spice to taste.
Thanks!
Kita-chan, eat!
Okay!
When she said she had friends coming,
I assumed they were imaginary
or hallucinations,
but then, she did have that picture...
Hallucinations?
But of course, image editing software
is pretty sophisticated these days...
Software?
If I might ask, you're not from
some kind of friend rental servi—
We're her bona fide bandmates!
Oh, okay.
I can't say it doesn't sound
like something I'd do...
It's just that Hitori's never
brought a friend home before.
but hearing Mom and Dad's
ideas about me is so...
So Bocchi's like this even at home.
She's been so restless for days now.
She said something about practicing
decorating her room,
put it all up, took it all down,
and put it back up, over and over again.
And she played a simulated game of Twister,
just in case you played.
M-Mom! Dad!
You don't have to tell them all that stuff!
I'm glad we went shopping just in case!
Okay, this is a day worth remembering!
A friend-a-versary!
Friend-a-versity!
C-Cut it out already!
That's right.
The job she said she'd gotten...
Yeah, it's at my sister's club.
Bocchi-chan mainly serves
drinks to customers.
T-To customers?!
Yeah!
It does feel pretty weird to
have friends at my house...
Am I dreaming?
Amazing. Music really does
cause personal growth!
And you were having so much fun
when we burst in like that!
I'm so sorry.
Maybe we should butt out?
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
Hey, hey, Kita-chan!
What's this?
That's my favorite heartwarming movie!
I've always wanted to watch that one!
Wanna watch it all together?
Yes, please!
Great idea! What fun!
Yeah! So fun! So fun! Yeah!
Alienation
I don't know why, but... it feels
kind of hard to go back in now...
Alienation
Welcome!  Members of Kessoku Band
We Hope Your Time Here Heals You in Both Mind and Body
The large Typhoon #8 remains on the move,
Typhoon #8
(As of 9th, 4 pm)
Size: _
Power: Strong
Dir/Spd: East 120 km/h
Pressure at Eye: 970 hPa
Max. Wind Speed: 35 m/s
Max. Gusts: 50 m/s
Upcoming Weather: Typhoon #8 Passes South of Japan
and will lose strength while
passing to the south of Japan...
With new house rules!
More exciting than ever!
Thinking of You
Kisses Over Flowers
At parties!
With family! As couples!
We ended up watching the movie,
playing games, and having nothing but fun.
Twister and Tycoon were so much fun to play!
Yeah! So much fun!
And yet...
That's right! We still need to design
our T-shirts for the concert.
Oh, wait...
Senpai! Gotoh-san's back to it!
Oh, I know why.
Watching that heartwarming seishun movie
has her back in a spiral.
Heartwarming
Seishun Movie
Heartwarming seishun movies:
I did it again?!
the number-one source of movie
trauma for introverts, by genre.
Traumatic Movie Genres for Introverts
1st Place
(Based on Japanese Introvert Society Poll)
Parentheses, based on Japanese
Introvert Society poll, close—
Bocchi-chan! We're running
out of time! Snap out of it!
A-An ordinary girl has two hot
guys trying to win her heart...
Gotoh-san!
It's hopeless.
But if someone that cute is "ordinary,"
what hope is there for me?
Ryo sent in a bunch of design ideas!
Let me see! I want to see!
C'mon! Look with us, Bocchi-chan!
Wh-What in the world?
Curry?
Now sushi...
I don't get it.
Which should I have for dinner?
Fried Rice
Ramen Set
Make your own decisions!
"I think curry's better!"
Kita-chan, don't actually respond!
E-Excuse me...
Hey, Bocchi-chan's back?
Y-Yes...
I thought you might like to see my design...
Let's Draw
What do you think?
S-So cringe!
I-Is it too trendy?
It's that mystery font I see on bottom text memes all the time.
I thought it would keep people focused
on our clothing when we're playing.
Yeah, for several reasons.
What's the point of all
the zippers and chains?
I thought I could use
the zippers to hold picks,
and the chain could serve
as a guitar strap.
Weirdly practical!
So, can I assume we're all in on this one?
I'm not sure about that...
Is this what you like to wear normally?
My mom buys my clothes, so no.
Oh, really?
I've never worn any of them, though...
They're not to my taste.
Aw, I wanna see!
Same! I've never seen you in
anything but the tracksuit!
C'mon, please! Try one on!
Please! Please!
Please! Please! Please!
F-Fine...
Yeah!
She's so...
C-Cute!
I love it! Look right this way!
N-No pictures, please...
I knew it! Bocchi-chan is drippin'!
It's easy to forget, with how she usually is!
U-Um... c-can I take it off now?
Wait, hang on!
I know!
Let's brush back your bangs!
That's what you need!
Are you growing them out?
I j-just can't get to the salon,
so they grow out...
Then I'll do some styling!
N-No, thank you!
Aw, don't be shy!
Bocchi-chan's turning into Hiroshima!
Her body can't keep up with the sudden
stress of her face being exposed!
Bocchi-chan's... dead.
We'll have to find a new guitarist.
Senpai! What's wrong?
I'm suddenly so dizzy...
The room is so damp all of a sudden,
like all the air's been sucked out of it...
I breathed it in!
S-So did I!
I-It's no use. G-Going limp...
Is this... Gotoh-san's curse?
Would anyone like dessert?
We've got the sweets Kita-chan brought—
I'm sorry for trying to push
through everything with positivity.
I'm sorry I couldn't get good at guitar.
I'm sorry for being too cute.
They're all acting like Sis!
Dear, the salt and the seals!
Should I call that exorcist?
Nijika
You'll have to do the concert yourself.
Why?
Several Days Later
And so...
Since nobody had any good ideas,
we're going with my T-shirt design!
Ta-dah.
Kessoku Band
I love it!
Did you make this, Ijichi-senpai?!
I'm pretty good at the design stuff!
Then why didn't you just
design it from the start?
Bocchi-chan.
You look like you were just thinking,
"Then why didn't you just design it from the start?"
Sh-She's psychic!
Let's Draw
I'm getting pretty good at
guessing what you're thinking lately!
Awesome! Our ties feel so much stronger now!
Yeah, I love it!
The quality of the model helps.
Kessoku Band
Totally!
Senpai, look right here!
This is pretty good, though.
Two days to our concert.
And we worked hard to make our ties feel...
Hey, looks like there's a typhoon on the way.
No way! This is the first I've heard of it!
Summer weather is so fickle.
Seriously?
B-But what about the concert?
Should we make rain charms?
Yeah! That's our only choice!
Your quota is ten each!
R-Right!
Oh, it looks like it won't
hit the Kanto region, though.
Oh, really?
Whew, that's a relief!
I can't wait for the show!
Yeah.
I think the new song's coming
together pretty well!
U-Um...
Yeah! We're all sounding awesome!
Okay, let's get practicing!
Excuse me!
Sh-Shouldn't we still make the
rain charms? Just to be safe?
Yeah, sure! Better safe than sorry, right?
Totally!
I'll bring in what we need to make them.
O-Okay!
I haven't made rain charms
since elementary school!
I'm used to being negative,
so I always assume the worst, but...
Sorry, the five younger brothers
I haven't seen since birth—
Stop acting above it! It was your idea!
You okay, Bocchi-chan?
Y-Y-Y-Y-Yes!
Kessoku Band
It'll be okay... I think.
Course Changed to Make Landfall
Look Out for Strong Winds and Heavy Rain
Typhoon #8
(As of 14th, 8 am)
Size: _
Power: Intense
Dir/Spd: Northeast 180 km/h
Pressure at Eye: 930 hPa
Max. Wind Speed: 60 m/s
Max. Gusts: 85 m/s
Typhoon #8 has taken an unexpected course...
DAY OF THE CONCERT
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can't beat that feeling
of being loved, it's true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It's time to take that step
Though there's nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It's time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I've been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I'm going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#08 Bocchi the Rock
Watch it!