Let's recap the show!!
Let's recap the show so far!
Hitori Gotoh is a slightly shy, socially
anxious, and isolated guitar enthusiast!
This guitar's my friend!
But some day, I might like to join a band!
And as she was thinking that...
Hey, come join our band!
From that humble beginning, she formed a rock
band with this group of colorful characters!
Since then, her life has been
one event after another!
And just now, the club manager said,
"I can't put you on stage
unless you pass an audition,"
which inspired a huge panic!
Manager's             Authority
Menacing
And after hours and hours of practice...
Pass
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
They managed to pass their audition!
Happiness bloomed!
Or so they thought, but Hitori Gotoh
still had a towering wall before her!
It was...
That five-person ticket quota!
What was a girl with no contacts
outside of her family and band to do?!
What will you do?
What will you do, Hitori—
Only ten days to the concert.
Last Night
Father, mother, sister, dog.
One ticket left for...
Grandma?
B-But I doubt she'd make the three-hour trip
just to see me play...
Good.
You know Jimihen can't come, right?
Y-You think?
I s-sort of had a feeling,
but... I wasn't sure...
Futari can't go to a club like that either.
She's only five.
Aw, no fun!
It's scary in there.
STARRY NIGHT
ahoge / Kessoku Band / Macaroni Pencil / Ryokuoushoku Yasai
(all four bands) [Alphabetical Order]
8/14
open 18:00       start 18:30
adv ¥1,500       door ¥2,000
Plus 1 Drink ¥500
Mother, father.
Mother, father...
I could invite some of my friends.
My friends.
Mother?
It's not like Sis has friends of her own!
I-I might not talk about them,
but I've got lots of friends at school.
Lia—
You shouldn't say that, even as a joke.
You should grow up to have
empathy for others.
S-Sorry.
Sounds like I should talk to my friends.
Me too—
N-N-N—
N-No, that's okay!
I've got lots of friends at school.
S-See?!
You just wait for that concert!
I shouldn't have bragged like that.
What do I do? If I don't find buyers
for three more tickets...
Kessoku Band
I made these promotional flyers to hand out
around my neighborhood, but...
Kessoku Band
Mainly playing at clubs in the city
Four-girl rock band
I read online that stuff with a handmade feel
comes across as more charming!
But honestly...
How is someone with social anxiety
supposed to hand out flyers?
I feel so powerless.
I'm too scared to even move.
Looks like lots of my friends are coming!
Thank goodness~~~~
Looks like lots of my friends
are coming! Thank goodness!
I got 'em sold
I got 'em sold.
How are you doing, Bocchi-chan? Coming to practice today?
I want to try the new song all together!
How are you doing,
Bocchi-chan? Coming today?
I want to try the new song all together!
Th-They're all taking care of it!
Wh-What do I say back?
"I got that quota covered!"
and pretend I'm okay?
Or do I just admit,
"I can't handle the quota!"?
But if I do that...
You can't be in the band
if you can't handle your quota.
Bye-bye, Bocchi.
Senpai!
I searched through my extensive connections
and found us an amazing and
totally extroverted guitarist!
Yeah!
Rock you!
Yeah! Rock you!
Why couldn't I just accept my mom's help?!
A p-person's collapsed.
Wh-What do I do? I've got to say something...
Actually, I need an ambulance!
H-Hello?
This is the news for 4:30 pm...
W-Water... Please...
R-Right! I'll go buy some—
A-And hangover medicine.
R-Right!
And miso soup with clams...
And rice porridge too...
Preferably in a bed dressed with
freshly line-dried sheets...
Sh-She's very demanding.
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#06 Eight Views
For stomach upset
during a hangover
Yoi-Shaki
Clam
With the ornithine of 96 clams
Ah, right to the liver!
You're a lifesaver! Thanks so much!
I didn't think you'd really
buy me the miso soup!
I-It's nothing.
I wanna take off my head and power-wash it!
I ended up helping a very weird person.
I wanna take out my guts
and wring out all the alcohol!
W-Well, I should be going...
Say, what's your name?
H-Hitori Gotoh.
What a cute name!
Th-Thank you.
Drinking should be done
in moderation, y'know?
She said as she started drinking again!
Hair of the dog that bit ya!
So good!
Onikoro Sake
She's still drinking.
What should I do? Just leave?
Ya want some too, Hitori-chan?
Sorry it's the cheap stuff.
N-No, thanks...
Wait, you're underage, right?
Hey, you listenin'?
Yeah, she's way too weird.
Why haven't ya said anything?
I can't tell if she's
serious or playing dumb.
Hitori-chan, you're cold as ice!
Like concrete!
On the count of three, I book it!
Wh-Whaddya want?
Ya want some booze after all?
I sh-should be going...
Hey, a guitar!
Do ya play?
I'm in a band too! Indie, of course.
Sh-She plays too?!
Hey, can ya play?
I'm s-s-s-so scared!
I've never talked to a
grown-up rocker before!
I d-don't know why, but I bet she'll be mad!
Lemme see
Lemme see! Lemme see!
Sheesh, kids these days...
You don't know what rock is!
I have to get out of here
before I say something stupid.
What's with you, Hitori-chan?
A-A-A-Actually I bought it
but gave up after one day,
so I was just heading
to a pawn shop to sell it!
Uh?
I was hoping for a far more worthy
person to use this guitar
and truly find their wings and soar,
but I d-d-don't play at all!
Sorry! Gosh, wonder how much I'll get for it!
It's all-you-can-eat yakiniku for me today!
Wait!
Giving up after one day is a waste.
You can sell it any time you want.
But if you stick with it
a little while longer,
you might become worthy
of that guitar someday.
Oh, listen to me! Tryin' to sound all wise...
Wait. Is she kind of normal after all?
Oh, I know.
How's about I give you lessons?
Oh, actually, sorry...
I lied about everything I said just now.
That's a heck of a smooth lie you told.
Wow, nice guitar!
It's clear you take good care of it.
Th-Thank you.
I play bass.
Booze and the bass are
worth more to me than my life,
so I always keep them close by.
So, uh...
Where's your bass?
Tee hee hee
I left it at the pub.
Let's go grab it, Hitori-chan!
She values her life so little...
Hey, hey.
Have you heard back from Bocchi-chan?
Still left on read.
Maybe we shouldn't have
sent those LOINEs.
I don't think that's it.
Today's our practice day.
I'm sure she's just busy.
Read 3
Stuck In
Quota Hell
Kita
Looks like lots of my friends are coming!
Thank goodness~~~~
Ryo
I got 'em sold
Read 3
How are you doing, Bocchi-chan?
Coming to practice today?
I want to try the new song all together!
You okay?
You think?
But what if we overwhelmed her?
I get how she feels.
Sob sob sob
I've felt that pressure so many times myself.
Yeah, right!
Sheesh...
Boy, I sure hope she's okay!
Ta-dah! My very own bass!
Th-This is all too incomprehensible.
Super Ultra Shuten Doji EX!
I'm struggling.
Cool, huh?
Y-Yes. Very cool.
We really rocked the house
at our concert last night!
But I drank way too much at the afterparty.
Next thing I knew, the sun was up,
and I had no idea where I was!
H-How many hours did you spend drinking?
Lesse...
The afterparty started at ten, so...
I was pretty out of it
most of the time, so...
Figure I might as well stay up 'til tonight.
Y-You really like drinking that much?
Sure do! Drinking lets me forget
everything, so I just...
Everything?
You know, like fears about the future.
Pension problems!
Rural depopulation! The poverty gap!
Fears about the future
Caregiving
Pension crisis
Stressful society
Low wages
Marriage
Loss of lifetime careers
Depression
Job searches
Rural
depopulation
Helplessness
Old age
Poverty gap
Unable to think of
anything but alcohol
I'm out of alcohol!
The alcohol is gone!
fidget fidget
Gotta get booze!
Life is pain
More, more!
Body builds up tolerance,
gotta drink more
Craving is temporarily
satisfied
Happiness Spiral
I call it a Happiness Spiral!
Kids, try this at home!
Um...
What a sad kind of happiness.
Doesn't ring true, huh?
You'll understand when
you're older, Hitori-chan.
A-Actually...
I'd really rather I didn't!
You'll be super into drinking, I bet!
I can tell just by looking at your face!
I wonder what I'd look like drunk...
XX Years Later
Mom's stopped bugging me to
go to the employment agency.
Bet she's too busy with her grandkids.
[SakeKowa]  Scary stories about booze
Search Articles                            Search
Categories
Scary stories about booze (9586)
Indoor (3200)
Outdoor (6386)
Popular Articles
[SakeKowa] Warping dimensions
[SakeKowa] My wallet feels lighter
[SakeKowa] I wake up to find...
[SakeKowa] Injury
[SakeKowa] Forgetfulness
[SakeKowa] Impromptu karaoke
Futari's a mama now, after all.
I know it's not good for
things to stay this way,
Popular Articles
[SakeKowa] Warping dimensions
[SakeKowa] My wallet feels lighter
[SakeKowa] I wake up to find...
[SakeKowa] Injury
[SakeKowa] Forgetfulness
[SakeKowa] Impromptu karaoke
[SakeKowa] Mega-size fried rice
[SakeKowa] Samba rhythm
[SakeKowa] Lost glasses
[SakeKowa] Fell head-over-heels
but I don't see how I could
pull myself together now.
Those high school days in the band...
Feels like a lifetime ago.
Boy, I sure was shining back then...
Wonder what they're all up to now.
But what would I even say if I saw them?
aaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaa
Wow, you're pretty messed up, too!
S-S-Sorry. I lost my head.
That's okay. I kinda like it.
By the way, what were ya doing?
A-Actually...
Explaining
Lorem ipsum, yada yada,
etc etc, blah blah blah...
Ah, I see!
Sob
I never knew you lived such a tragic life!
Sh-She's really sympathetic!
Selling tickets is so hard.
I really struggled with it at the start too!
Y-Yeah, it really is...
Okay, since you saved my life,
I'm gonna put some skin in the game.
Now, prepare yourself.
You and I are gonna...
play a street concert, right here and now!
S-Street concert?
Yeah! You've got those flyers, after all.
The best way to sell tickets is to play
on the street and pick up an audience.
B-But...
Seems there's some kind of
festival in the area today,
Traffic Pattern
Announcement
Today
Vehicles prohibited at this time.
We kindly request your cooperation.
so there's lots of people around.
Perfect for a street performance!
Oh, but we don't have amps and stuff...
T-Too bad! Guess we'll have
to try another time...
H-Hey, it's me!
Yeah, I'm not dead!
I was gonna play on the street,
so could you bring the stuff by for that?
Nah, the equipment's enough.
Wh-What do I do? She's really going for it...
Yeah.
Sure, thanks!
Kessoku Band
Mainly playing at clubs in the city
Four-girl rock band
Shimo-Kitazawa STARRY
Hey, everyone!
We're about to play!
It's free, so come by if you can!
Hey, Kanazawa-Hakkei peeps!
We're about to play!
Come watch!
Wow!
I can't wait!
You're playing, girl!
Huh? You've never played outside before?
If you're that scared,
you could shut your eyes...
Or... Well, I guess you're
scared of strangers, huh?
Oh, that might just work...
I feel you.
I've been playing so long in the dark
where I can't see my fingers anyway.
Yeah. I can do it.
But just so you know...
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
You're not in combat with
the people in front of you.
Don't get it twisted who your enemies are.
Enemies?
What does she mean, enemies?
What? What's Gotoh-san like at school?
Yeah.
I think I can kind of picture it,
but... well...
Is she a loner at school, too?
Don't just say it like that!
Well, let me see...
We're in different classes, so I don't see
what she's like with her classmates, but...
It's true that I've never seen her
with another person.
Oh, she's not being bullied
or anything, though.
That's good to hear!
She's really withdrawn and people seem
to have trouble interacting with her.
It's kind of hard to know
how to approach her.
Really?
But Bocchi's so fun.
I know, right?!
Okay, we're starting!
We're playing an original song
by her band, Kessoku Band!
Let's have some applause!
Go on, play.
R-Right...
She'll stick with me for guitar practice,
but when I invite her to have lunch
with my friends, she won't come,
and she's never in her classroom...
She's...
She's ad-libbing, but she's really selling it.
Her playing is so confident.
She's giving me such a firm
foundation to play from.
Just from hearing her play,
I can tell she's having fun.
By comparison, I...
I wonder if they're all
laughing at me out there.
I'm too scared to look up.
You're doing great!
Hey, what are you doing?
Well... The guitar girl seemed nervous,
so it just came out.
Just came out?
Thank goodness~~~~
Ryo
I got 'em sold
Read by 3
How are you doing, Bocchi-chan?
Coming to practice today?
I want to try the new song all together!
Bocchi-chan...
I sure hope she's okay...
I see.
I never had any enemies here.
It was just my imagination.
She opened her eyes.
Her playing is suddenly more stable.
So this is how Hitori-chan plays.
Interesting.
That's right.
The only people here are the ones
who stopped to hear you play.
Realizing and conquering her flaws
in such a short time... Amazing!
She's going to get better.
My instinct never lies!
They're all smiling.
If I do more concerts,
will I see more faces like these?
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
I think I'd like that.
Great work, Hitori-chan!
Th-Thank you.
Wh-What a relief...
She didn't realize I only had one eye open!
What's wrong?
Special Performance
Buy tickets, please!
— Kessoku Band —
1500 yen per ticket
Performing 8/14, 6PM
at Kitazawa STARRY
Oh, n-nothing...
Sorry. I can't change everything all at once!
Excuse me.
Y-Yes?!
Can we buy tickets to this concert?
We'll take two!
Isn't that great, Hitori-chan?
Huh? Did you freeze up from joy?
Um... That'll be 1,500 yen apiece, 3,000 total!
Right?
Y-Yes!
A-Are you sure you want
to buy those t-t-tickets?
Give it up already, Hitori-chan!
B-But I...
This was my first time watching a
street performance, but you were so good!
Keep up the good work at
your next concert, okay?
R-Right... I'll do my best.
Will you be playing that song again?
Onikoro
Y-Yes. I will.
Can't wait to see it!
To think I had this shining
period myself once...
Tonight, I drown away my cares.
Wh-Why are you crying?
Sorry, sorry!
I'll be back in my happiness spiral soon...
Th-That can't possibly be good for you.
Excuse me. You guys can't play here!
Sorry!
I-It's the fuzz!
Are they gonna take me away?!
Of course not!
They are pretty mad, though,
so let's call it quits here.
Oh, that's right.
I got so carried away before, but I
still have one ticket left to sell...
B-But I did sell four!
Not bad for my first time!
I'll buy that last one.
The ticket.
That'll get you to your quota, right?
Y-You're sure?!
Of course. I typically operate
out of Shinjuku, so I'm close by,
and I know this club too.
Th-Thank you so much...
A concert costing over five Onikoros...
It'd better be worth it!
R-Right!
Let's play together again some time!
Bye-bye, Hitori-chan!
What a mysterious person.
Rockers really are...
cool.
I spent the last of my money on your ticket!
Can I borrow some for the train?
I'll pay you back at the concert.
This feels strangely familiar.
Achoo!
Why are rockers all so poor?
Wow!
I'm sorry I didn't make it to practice today.
Also...
I sold all my tickets!
And... send!
May our concert be a big success!
"Also, I sold all
my tickets," she said!
Bocchi-chan...
She's totally lying, right?
Totally.
I bet our LOINEs really
did put pressure on her.
Poor thing.
Let's all be nice to her
at practice tomorrow!
Sure.
Right!
I sleep, with big problems
weighing down on me
Though you can't beat that feeling
of being loved, it's true
When I awaken from cold dreams,
my body feels numb
You shine so brightly,
it could make me a shadow
It's time to take that step
Though there's nothing certain about it
It carries my childish heart into tomorrow
It's time to blast out the thoughts
rattling around in my brain
And live, to its fullest, a life
I've been taking advances on for so long
But I also love the days I spend
lying around, doing nothing
So I know I'm going to go see you
Before it all disappears some day
#07  To Your House
Wash'it!